<definition xmlns="http://oval.mitre.org/XMLSchema/oval-definitions-5" class="patch" id="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:15374" version="21">
  <metadata>
    <title>DSA-2358-1 openjdk-6 -- several</title>
    <affected family="unix">
      <platform>Debian GNU/Linux 5.0</platform>
      <product>openjdk-6</product>
    </affected>
    <reference ref_id="DSA-2358-1" ref_url="http://lists.debian.org/debian-security-announce/2011/msg00236.html" source="VENDOR" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-0862" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-0862" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-0864" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-0864" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-0865" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-0865" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-0867" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-0867" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-0868" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-0868" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-0869" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-0869" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-0871" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-0871" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-3389" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-3389" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-3521" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-3521" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-3544" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-3544" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-3547" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-3547" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-3548" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-3548" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-3551" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-3551" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-3552" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-3552" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-3553" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-3553" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-3554" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-3554" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-3556" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-3556" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-3557" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-3557" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-3560" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-3560" source="CVE" />
    <description>Several vulnerabilities have been discovered in OpenJDK, an implementation of the Java platform. This combines the two previous openjdk-6 advisories, DSA-2311-1 and DSA-2356-1. CVE-2011-0862 Integer overflow errors in the JPEG and font parser allow untrusted code to elevate its privileges. CVE-2011-0864 Hotspot, the just-in-time compiler in OpenJDK, mishandled certain byte code instructions, allowing untrusted code to crash the virtual machine. CVE-2011-0865 A race condition in signed object deserialization could allow untrusted code to modify signed content, apparently leaving its signature intact. CVE-2011-0867 Untrusted code could access information about network interfaces which was not intended to be public. CVE-2011-0868 A float-to-long conversion could overflow, allowing untrusted code to crash the virtual machine. CVE-2011-0869 Untrusted code could intercept HTTP requests by reconfiguring proxy settings through a SOAP connection. CVE-2011-0871 Untrusted code could elevate its privileges through the Swing MediaTracker code. CVE-2011-3389 The TLS implementation does not guard properly against certain chosen-plaintext attacks when block ciphers are used in CBC mode. CVE-2011-3521 The CORBA implementation contains a deserialization vulnerability in the IIOP implementation, allowing untrusted Java code to elevate its privileges. CVE-2011-3544 The Java scripting engine lacks necessary security manager checks, allowing untrusted Java code to elevate its privileges. CVE-2011-3547 The skip method in java.io.InputStream uses a shared buffer, allowing untrusted Java code to access data that is skipped by other code. CVE-2011-3548 The java.awt.AWTKeyStroke class contains a flaw which allows untrusted Java code to elevate its privileges. CVE-2011-3551 The Java2D C code contains an integer overflow which results in a heap-based buffer overflow, potentially allowing untrusted Java code to elevate its privileges. CVE-2011-3552 Malicous Java code can use up an excessive amount of UDP ports, leading to a denial of service. CVE-2011-3553 JAX-WS enables stack traces for certain server responses by default, potentially leaking sensitive information. CVE-2011-3554 JAR files in pack200 format are not properly checked for errors, potentially leading to arbitrary code execution when unpacking crafted pack200 files. CVE-2011-3556 The RMI Registry server lacks access restrictions on certain methods, allowing a remote client to execute arbitary code. CVE-2011-3557 The RMI Registry server fails to properly restrict privileges of untrusted Java code, allowing RMI clients to elevate their privileges on the RMI Registry server. CVE-2011-3560 The com.sun.net.ssl.HttpsURLConnection class does not perform proper security manager checks in the setSSLSocketFactory method, allowing untrusted Java code to bypass security policy restrictions.</description>
    <oval_repository>
      <dates>
        <submitted date="2012-03-29T02:10:09-05:00">
          <contributor organization="SecPod Technologies">SecPod Team</contributor>
        </submitted>
        <status_change date="2012-03-29T10:57:04.628-04:00">DRAFT</status_change>
        <status_change date="2012-04-16T04:07:37.075-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2012-05-07T04:02:05.902-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
        <modified comment="EDITED oval:org.mitre.oval:def:15374 - Debian Patch Update" date="2014-06-06T17:34:00.215-04:00">
          <contributor organization="ALTX-SOFT">Sergey Artykhov</contributor>
        </modified>
        <status_change date="2014-06-06T17:36:32.541-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-06-23T04:03:45.156-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
      </dates>
      <status>ACCEPTED</status>
      <min_schema_version>5.4</min_schema_version>
    </oval_repository>
  </metadata>
  <criteria>
    <extend_definition comment="Debian GNU/Linux 5.0 is installed" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:6513" />
    <criterion comment="Installed architecture is all" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:10881" />
    <criterion comment="openjdk-6 DPKG is earlier than 6b18-1.8.10-0~lenny1" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:78586" />
  </criteria>
</definition>
