<definition xmlns="http://oval.mitre.org/XMLSchema/oval-definitions-5" class="patch" id="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:27070" version="14">
  <metadata>
    <title>RHSA-2013:0519 -- openssh security, bug fix and enhancement update (Moderate)</title>
    <affected family="unix">
      <platform>Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6</platform>
      <platform>CentOS Linux 6</platform>
      <product>openssh</product>
    </affected>
    <reference ref_id="RHSA-2013:0519" ref_url="https://rhn.redhat.com/errata/RHSA-2013-0519.html" source="VENDOR" />
    <reference ref_id="CESA-2013:0519" ref_url="http://lists.centos.org/pipermail/centos-cr-announce/2013-February/000649.html" source="CESA-2013:0519" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2012-5536" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2012-5536" source="CVE" />
    <description>OpenSSH is OpenBSD&amp;#39;s Secure Shell (SSH) protocol implementation. These
packages include the core files necessary for the OpenSSH client and
server.

Due to the way the pam_ssh_agent_auth PAM module was built in Red Hat
Enterprise Linux 6, the glibc&amp;#39;s error() function was called rather than the
intended error() function in pam_ssh_agent_auth to report errors. As these
two functions expect different arguments, it was possible for an attacker
to cause an application using pam_ssh_agent_auth to crash, disclose
portions of its memory or, potentially, execute arbitrary code.
(CVE-2012-5536)

Note that the pam_ssh_agent_auth module is not used in Red Hat Enterprise
Linux 6 by default.

This update also fixes the following bugs:

* All possible options for the new RequiredAuthentications directive were
not documented in the sshd_config man page. This update improves the man
page to document all the possible options. (BZ#821641)

* When stopping one instance of the SSH daemon (sshd), the sshd init script
(/etc/rc.d/init.d/sshd) stopped all sshd processes regardless of the PID of
the processes. This update improves the init script so that it only kills
processes with the relevant PID. As a result, the init script now works
more reliably in a multi-instance environment. (BZ#826720)

* Due to a regression, the ssh-copy-id command returned an exit status code
of zero even if there was an error in copying the key to a remote host.
With this update, a patch has been applied and ssh-copy-id now returns a
non-zero exit code if there is an error in copying the SSH certificate to a
remote host. (BZ#836650)

* When SELinux was disabled on the system, no on-disk policy was installed,
a user account was used for a connection, and no &amp;quot;~/.ssh&amp;quot; configuration was
present in that user&amp;#39;s home directory, the SSH client terminated
unexpectedly with a segmentation fault when attempting to connect to
another system. A patch has been provided to address this issue and the
crashes no longer occur in the described scenario. (BZ#836655)

* The &amp;quot;HOWTO&amp;quot; document /usr/share/doc/openssh-ldap-5.3p1/HOWTO.ldap-keys
incorrectly documented the use of the AuthorizedKeysCommand directive.
This update corrects the document. (BZ#857760)

This update also adds the following enhancements:

* When attempting to enable SSH for use with a Common Access Card (CAC),
the ssh-agent utility read all the certificates in the card even though
only the ID certificate was needed. Consequently, if a user entered their
PIN incorrectly, then the CAC was locked, as a match for the PIN was
attempted against all three certificates. With this update, ssh-add does
not try the same PIN for every certificate if the PIN fails for the first
one. As a result, the CAC will not be disabled if a user enters their PIN
incorrectly. (BZ#782912)

* This update adds a &amp;quot;netcat mode&amp;quot; to SSH. The &amp;quot;ssh -W host:port ...&amp;quot;
command connects standard input and output (stdio) on a client to a single
port on a server. As a result, SSH can be used to route connections via
intermediate servers. (BZ#860809)

* Due to a bug, arguments for the RequiredAuthentications2 directive were
not stored in a Match block. Consequently, parsing of the config file was
not in accordance with the man sshd_config documentation. This update fixes
the bug and users can now use the required authentication feature to
specify a list of authentication methods as expected according to the man
page. (BZ#869903)

All users of openssh are advised to upgrade to these updated packages,
which fix these issues and add these enhancements. After installing this
update, the OpenSSH server daemon (sshd) will be restarted automatically.</description>
    <oval_repository>
      <dates>
        <submitted date="2014-10-28T18:16:04">
          <contributor organization="ALTX-SOFT">Sergey Artykhov</contributor>
        </submitted>
        <status_change date="2014-10-29T12:47:36.814-04:00">DRAFT</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-11-17T04:01:41.072-05:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-12-08T04:00:35.124-05:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
        <modified comment="EDITED oval:org.mitre.oval:obj:42383 - Updated States &amp; Objects" date="2015-02-02T15:56:00.526-05:00">
          <contributor organization="ALTX-SOFT">Maria Mikhno</contributor>
        </modified>
        <status_change date="2015-02-02T16:00:51.384-05:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2015-02-23T04:00:53.473-05:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
      </dates>
      <status>ACCEPTED</status>
      <min_schema_version>5.3</min_schema_version>
    </oval_repository>
  </metadata>
  <criteria operator="OR">
    <criteria comment="Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6 release section">
      <extend_definition comment="The operating system installed on the system is Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:20273" />
      <criterion comment="openssh-debuginfo is earlier than 0:5.3p1-84.1.el6" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:125987" />
    </criteria>
    <criteria comment="Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6 and CentOS Linux 6 release section">
      <criteria comment="Operation system section" operator="OR">
        <extend_definition comment="The operating system installed on the system is Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:20273" />
        <extend_definition comment="The operating system installed on the system is CentOS Linux 6.x" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:16337" />
      </criteria>
      <criteria comment="Packages match section" operator="OR">
        <criterion comment="openssh is earlier than 0:5.3p1-84.1.el6" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:125479" />
        <criterion comment="openssh-askpass is earlier than 0:5.3p1-84.1.el6" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:126146" />
        <criterion comment="openssh-clients is earlier than 0:5.3p1-84.1.el6" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:126032" />
        <criterion comment="openssh-ldap is earlier than 0:5.3p1-84.1.el6" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:125331" />
        <criterion comment="openssh-server is earlier than 0:5.3p1-84.1.el6" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:126182" />
        <criterion comment="pam_ssh_agent_auth is earlier than 0:0.9.3-84.1.el6" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:126124" />
      </criteria>
    </criteria>
  </criteria>
</definition>
