<definition xmlns="http://oval.mitre.org/XMLSchema/oval-definitions-5" class="patch" id="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:24802" version="13">
  <metadata>
    <title>RHSA-2014:0561: curl security and bug fix update (Moderate)</title>
    <affected family="unix">
      <platform>Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6</platform>
      <platform>CentOS Linux 6</platform>
      <product>curl</product>
    </affected>
    <reference ref_id="RHSA-2014:0561-00" ref_url="https://rhn.redhat.com/errata/RHSA-2014-0561.html" source="VENDOR" />
    <reference ref_id="CESA-2014:0561" source="CESA" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2014-0015" ref_url="https://www.redhat.com/security/data/cve/CVE-2014-0015.html" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2014-0138" ref_url="https://www.redhat.com/security/data/cve/CVE-2014-0138.html" source="CVE" />
    <description>cURL provides the libcurl library and a command line tool for downloading
files from servers using various protocols, including HTTP, FTP, and LDAP.

It was found that libcurl could incorrectly reuse existing connections for
requests that should have used different or no authentication credentials,
when using one of the following protocols: HTTP(S) with NTLM
authentication, LDAP(S), SCP, or SFTP. If an application using the libcurl
library connected to a remote server with certain authentication
credentials, this flaw could cause other requests to use those same
credentials. (CVE-2014-0015, CVE-2014-0138)

Red Hat would like to thank the cURL project for reporting these issues.
Upstream acknowledges Paras Sethia as the original reporter of
CVE-2014-0015 and Yehezkel Horowitz for discovering the security impact of
this issue, and Steve Holme as the original reporter of CVE-2014-0138.

This update also fixes the following bugs:

* Previously, the libcurl library was closing a network socket without
first terminating the SSL connection using the socket. This resulted in a
write after close and consequent leakage of memory dynamically allocated by
the SSL library. An upstream patch has been applied on libcurl to fix this
bug. As a result, the write after close no longer happens, and the SSL
library no longer leaks memory. (BZ#1092479)

* Previously, the libcurl library did not implement a non-blocking SSL
handshake, which negatively affected performance of applications based on
libcurl's multi API. To fix this bug, the non-blocking SSL handshake has
been implemented by libcurl. With this update, libcurl's multi API
immediately returns the control back to the application whenever it cannot
read/write data from/to the underlying network socket. (BZ#1092480)

* Previously, the curl package could not be rebuilt from sources due to an
expired cookie in the upstream test-suite, which runs during the build. An
upstream patch has been applied to postpone the expiration date of the
cookie, which makes it possible to rebuild the package from sources again.
(BZ#1092486)

* Previously, the libcurl library attempted to authenticate using Kerberos
whenever such an authentication method was offered by the server. This
caused problems when the server offered multiple authentication methods and
Kerberos was not the selected one. An upstream patch has been applied on
libcurl to fix this bug. Now libcurl no longer uses Kerberos authentication
if another authentication method is selected. (BZ#1096797)

All curl users are advised to upgrade to these updated packages, which
contain backported patches to correct these issues. All running
applications that use libcurl have to be restarted for this update to
take effect.</description>
    <oval_repository>
      <dates>
        <submitted date="2014-06-09T15:16:45">
          <contributor organization="ALTX-SOFT">Sergey Artykhov</contributor>
        </submitted>
        <status_change date="2014-06-10T14:50:20.503-04:00">DRAFT</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-06-30T04:10:54.065-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-07-21T04:01:42.248-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
      </dates>
      <status>ACCEPTED</status>
      <min_schema_version>5.3</min_schema_version>
    </oval_repository>
  </metadata>
  <criteria>
    <criteria comment="Redhat 6 or Centos 6 release" operator="OR">
      <extend_definition comment="The operating system installed on the system is Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:20273" />
      <extend_definition comment="The operating system installed on the system is CentOS Linux 6.x" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:16337" />
    </criteria>
    <criteria comment="Packages section" operator="OR">
      <criterion comment="curl is earlier than 0:7.19.7-37.el6_5.3" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:114394" />
      <criterion comment="libcurl is earlier than 0:7.19.7-37.el6_5.3" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:114787" />
      <criterion comment="libcurl-devel is earlier than 0:7.19.7-37.el6_5.3" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:114569" />
    </criteria>
  </criteria>
</definition>
