<definition xmlns="http://oval.mitre.org/XMLSchema/oval-definitions-5" class="patch" id="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:22676" version="14">
  <metadata>
    <title>ELSA-2008:1045: java-1.6.0-bea security update (Important)</title>
    <affected family="unix">
      <platform>Oracle Linux 5</platform>
      <product>java-1.6.0-bea</product>
    </affected>
    <reference ref_id="ELSA-2008:1045-01" ref_url="http://linux.oracle.com/errata/ELSA-2008-1045.html" source="VENDOR" />
    <description>The BEA WebLogic JRockit JRE and SDK contains BEA WebLogic JRockit Virtual
Machine and is certified for the Java™ 2 Platform, Standard Edition,
v1.6.0.
The java-1.6.0-bea packages are vulnerable to important security flaws and
should no longer be used.
A flaw was found in the Java Management Extensions (JMX) management agent.
When local monitoring was enabled, remote attackers could use this flaw to
perform illegal operations. (CVE-2008-3103)
Several flaws involving the handling of unsigned applets were found. A
remote attacker could misuse an unsigned applet in order to connect to
services on the host running the applet. (CVE-2008-3104)
Several flaws in the Java API for XML Web Services (JAX-WS) client and the
JAX-WS service implementation were found. A remote attacker who could cause
malicious XML to be processed by an application could access URLs, or cause
a denial of service. (CVE-2008-3105, CVE-2008-3106)
Several flaws within the Java Runtime Environment's (JRE) scripting support
were found. A remote attacker could grant an untrusted applet extended
privileges, such as reading and writing local files, executing local
programs, or querying the sensitive data of other applets. (CVE-2008-3109,
CVE-2008-3110)
The vulnerabilities concerning applets listed above can only be triggered
in java-1.6.0-bea, by calling the "appletviewer" application.
BEA was acquired by Oracle® during 2008 (the acquisition was completed on
April 29, 2008). Consequently, JRockit is now an Oracle offering and these
issues are addressed in the current release of Oracle JRockit. Due to a
license change by Oracle, however, Red Hat is unable to ship Oracle
JRockit.
Users who wish to continue using JRockit should get an update directly from
Oracle: http://oracle.com/technology/software/products/jrockit/.
Alternatives to Oracle JRockit include the Java 2 Technology Edition of the
IBM® Developer Kit for Linux and the Sun™ Java SE Development Kit (JDK),
both of which are available on the Extras or Supplementary channels. For
Java 6 users, the new OpenJDK open source JDK will be included in Red Hat
Enterprise Linux 5.3 and will be supported by Red Hat.
This update removes the java-1.6.0-bea packages due to their known security
vulnerabilities.</description>
    <oval_repository>
      <dates>
        <submitted date="2014-01-13T12:30:04.000-05:00">
          <contributor organization="Hewlett-Packard">Vinay Naikar</contributor>
        </submitted>
        <status_change date="2014-03-18T08:53:28.967-04:00">DRAFT</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-04-07T04:03:15.497-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-04-28T04:01:42.615-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
        <modified comment="EDITED oval:org.mitre.oval:def:22676 - optimisation of Oracle Linux content" date="2014-05-05T18:07:00.862-04:00">
          <contributor organization="ALTX-SOFT">Maria Mikhno</contributor>
        </modified>
        <status_change date="2014-05-05T18:09:14.972-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-05-26T04:01:48.548-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
      </dates>
      <status>ACCEPTED</status>
      <min_schema_version>5.3</min_schema_version>
    </oval_repository>
  </metadata>
  <criteria>
    <extend_definition comment="Oracle Linux 5.x" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:15459" />
    <criteria comment="rpm test" operator="OR">
      <criterion comment="java-1.6.0-bea-uninstall is earlier than 1:1.6.0.03-1jpp.6.el5" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:102737" />
      <criterion comment="java-1.6.0-bea is earlier than 1:1.6.0.03-1jpp.6.el5" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:102316" />
    </criteria>
  </criteria>
</definition>
