<definition xmlns="http://oval.mitre.org/XMLSchema/oval-definitions-5" class="patch" id="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:26646" version="4">
  <metadata>
    <title>RHSA-2014:1059: libvirt bug fix update (Low)</title>
    <affected family="unix">
      <platform>Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6</platform>
      <product>libvirt</product>
    </affected>
    <reference ref_id="RHSA-2014:1059-00" ref_url="https://rhn.redhat.com/errata/RHSA-2014-1059.html" source="VENDOR" />
    <description>The libvirt library is a C API for managing and interacting with the
virtualization capabilities of Linux and other operating systems. In addition,
libvirt provides tools for remote management of virtualized systems. 

This update fixes the following bugs:

* Previously, the libvirt API did not properly cancel the migration of QEMU
domains if it detected an error, which caused QEMU to pause guest CPUs. With
this update, if libvirt detects an error during a migration process, it informs
QEMU to cancel the ongoing migration. Now, after a failed migration, libvirt
resumes a domain, which then remains running, and QEMU no longer pauses guest
CPUs. (BZ#1100642)

* Prior to this update, the libvirt API canceled migration when it could not
access a QEMU monitor for more that 30 seconds to get migration status.
Consequently, when the libvirt user queried some data from QEMU during an
ongoing migration, the query timed out and libvirt canceled the migration. As a
workaround, ignore the time-out error and try querying again as libvirt checks
for migration status every 50ms. As a result, migration in a Red Hat Enterprise
Virtualization environment is no longer canceled when QEMU is slow to respond.
(BZ#1100671)

* Previously, a host device located on a PCI bus with a domain other than "0"
could not be assigned to a virtual guest using PCI passthrough. This bug has
been fixed, and QEMU is now able to assign non-0 domains in the PCI address. As
a result, host devices located on a PCI bus with a non-0 domain can now be
assigned to a guest as intended. (BZ#1100737)

Users of libvirt are advised to upgrade to these updated packages, which fix
these bugs. After installing the updated packages, libvirtd will be restarted
automatically.</description>
    <oval_repository>
      <dates>
        <submitted date="2014-09-26T11:25:02">
          <contributor organization="ALTX-SOFT">Sergey Artykhov</contributor>
        </submitted>
        <status_change date="2014-09-29T12:07:08.284-04:00">DRAFT</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-10-20T04:00:43.974-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-11-10T04:01:41.223-05:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
      </dates>
      <status>ACCEPTED</status>
      <min_schema_version>5.3</min_schema_version>
    </oval_repository>
  </metadata>
  <criteria>
    <extend_definition comment="The operating system installed on the system is Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:20273" />
    <criteria comment="Packages section" operator="OR">
      <criterion comment="libvirt is earlier than 0:0.10.2-29.el6_5.11" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:123844" />
      <criterion comment="libvirt-client is earlier than 0:0.10.2-29.el6_5.11" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:123675" />
      <criterion comment="libvirt-devel is earlier than 0:0.10.2-29.el6_5.11" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:123569" />
      <criterion comment="libvirt-lock-sanlock is earlier than 0:0.10.2-29.el6_5.11" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:123423" />
      <criterion comment="libvirt-python is earlier than 0:0.10.2-29.el6_5.11" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:123783" />
    </criteria>
  </criteria>
</definition>
