<definition xmlns="http://oval.mitre.org/XMLSchema/oval-definitions-5" class="patch" id="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:7247" version="21">
  <metadata>
    <title>DSA-1950 webkit -- several vulnerabilities</title>
    <affected family="unix">
      <platform>Debian GNU/Linux 5.0</platform>
      <product>webkit</product>
    </affected>
    <reference ref_id="DSA-1950" ref_url="http://www.debian.org/security/2009/dsa-1950" source="VENDOR" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2009-0945" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-0945" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2009-1687" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1687" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2009-1690" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1690" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2009-1698" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1698" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2009-1711" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1711" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2009-1712" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1712" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2009-1725" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1725" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2009-1714" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1714" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2009-1710" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1710" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2009-1697" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1697" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2009-1695" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1695" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2009-1693" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1693" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2009-1694" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1694" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2009-1681" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1681" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2009-1684" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1684" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2009-1692" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1692" source="CVE" />
    <description>Several vulnerabilities have been discovered in WebKit, a Web content engine library for Gtk+. The Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures project identifies the following problems: Array index error in the insertItemBefore method in WebKit, allows remote attackers to execute arbitrary code via a document with a SVGPathList data structure containing a negative index in the SVGTransformList, SVGStringList, SVGNumberList, SVGPathSegList, SVGPointList, or SVGLengthList SVGList object, which triggers memory corruption. The JavaScript garbage collector in WebKit does not properly handle allocation failures, which allows remote attackers to execute arbitrary code or cause a denial of service via a crafted HTML document that triggers write access to an "offset of a NULL pointer." Use-after-free vulnerability in WebKit, allows remote attackers to execute arbitrary code or cause a denial of service by setting an unspecified property of an HTML tag that causes child elements to be freed and later accessed when an HTML error occurs, related to "recursion in certain DOM event handlers." WebKit does not initialise a pointer during handling of a Cascading Style Sheets attr function call with a large numerical argument, which allows remote attackers to execute arbitrary code or cause a denial of service via a crafted HTML document. WebKit does not properly initialise memory for Attr DOM objects, which allows remote attackers to execute arbitrary code or cause a denial of service via a crafted HTML document. WebKit does not prevent remote loading of local Java applets, which allows remote attackers to execute arbitrary code, gain privileges, or obtain sensitive information via an APPLET or OBJECT element. WebKit do not properly handle numeric character references, which allows remote attackers to execute arbitrary code or cause a denial of service via a crafted HTML document. Cross-site scripting vulnerability in Web Inspector in WebKit allows user-assisted remote attackers to inject arbitrary web script or HTML, and read local files, via vectors related to the improper escaping of HTML attributes. WebKit allows remote attackers to spoof the browser's display of the host name, security indicators, and unspecified other UI elements via a custom cursor in conjunction with a modified CSS3 hotspot property. CRLF injection vulnerability in WebKit allows remote attackers to inject HTTP headers and bypass the Same Origin Policy via a crafted HTML document, related to cross-site scripting attacks that depend on communication with arbitrary web sites on the same server through use of XMLHttpRequest without a Host header. Cross-site scripting vulnerability in WebKit allows remote attackers to inject arbitrary web script or HTML via vectors involving access to frame contents after completion of a page transition. WebKit allows remote attackers to read images from arbitrary web sites via a CANVAS element with an SVG image, related to a "cross-site image capture issue." WebKit does not properly handle redirects, which allows remote attackers to read images from arbitrary web sites via vectors involving a CANVAS element and redirection, related to a "cross-site image capture issue." WebKit does not prevent web sites from loading third-party content into a subframe, which allows remote attackers to bypass the Same Origin Policy and conduct "clickjacking" attacks via a crafted HTML document. Cross-site scripting vulnerability in WebKit allows remote attackers to inject arbitrary web script or HTML via an event handler that triggers script execution in the context of the next loaded document. WebKit allows remote attackers to cause a denial of service via a web page containing an HTMLSelectElement object with a large length attribute, related to the length property of a Select object.</description>
    <oval_repository>
      <dates>
        <submitted date="2010-05-24T19:04:19-05:00">
          <contributor organization="SecPod Technologies">SecPod Team</contributor>
        </submitted>
        <status_change date="2010-05-26T13:27:50.462-04:00">DRAFT</status_change>
        <status_change date="2010-06-14T04:00:40.705-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2010-06-29T11:49:33.542-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
        <modified comment="EDITED oval:org.mitre.oval:def:7247 - Debian Patch Update" date="2014-06-06T16:48:00.629-04:00">
          <contributor organization="ALTX-SOFT">Sergey Artykhov</contributor>
        </modified>
        <status_change date="2014-06-06T16:49:46.717-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-06-23T04:08:14.570-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
      </dates>
      <status>ACCEPTED</status>
      <min_schema_version>5.4</min_schema_version>
    </oval_repository>
  </metadata>
  <criteria>
    <extend_definition comment="Debian GNU/Linux 5.0 is installed" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:6513" />
    <criteria comment="Architecture section" operator="OR">
      <criteria comment="Architecture independent section" operator="AND">
        <criterion comment="Installed architecture is all" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:10881" />
        <criterion comment="libwebkit-dev is earlier than 1.0.1-4+lenny2" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:25253" />
      </criteria>
      <criteria comment="Architecture dependent section" operator="AND">
        <criteria comment="Supported architectures section" operator="OR">
          <criterion comment="Installed architecture is s390" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:11024" />
          <criterion comment="Installed architecture is amd64" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:10392" />
          <criterion comment="Installed architecture is sparc" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:2465" />
          <criterion comment="Installed architecture is arm" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:10933" />
          <criterion comment="Installed architecture is i386" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:10864" />
          <criterion comment="Installed architecture is armel" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:11101" />
          <criterion comment="Installed architecture is mips" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:11195" />
          <criterion comment="Installed architecture is ia64" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:10830" />
          <criterion comment="Installed architecture is alpha" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:10654" />
          <criterion comment="Installed architecture is mipsel" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:11110" />
          <criterion comment="Installed architecture is hppa" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:11164" />
        </criteria>
        <criteria comment="Packages section" operator="OR">
          <criterion comment="libwebkit-1.0-1-dbg is earlier than 1.0.1-4+lenny2" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:25542" />
          <criterion comment="libwebkit-1.0-1 is earlier than 1.0.1-4+lenny2" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:25497" />
        </criteria>
      </criteria>
    </criteria>
  </criteria>
</definition>
