<definition xmlns="http://oval.mitre.org/XMLSchema/oval-definitions-5" class="patch" id="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:12997" version="22">
  <metadata>
    <title>DSA-2264-1 linux-2.6 -- privilege escalation/denial of service/information leak</title>
    <affected family="unix">
      <platform>Debian GNU/Linux 5.0</platform>
      <product>linux-2.6</product>
    </affected>
    <reference ref_id="DSA-2264-1" ref_url="http://lists.debian.org/debian-security-announce/2011/msg00134.html" source="VENDOR" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-2524" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-2524" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-3875" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-3875" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-4075" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-4075" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-4655" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-4655" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-0695" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-0695" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-0710" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-0710" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-0711" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-0711" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-0726" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-0726" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1010" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1010" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1012" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1012" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1017" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1017" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1078" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1078" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1079" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1079" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1080" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1080" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1090" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1090" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1093" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1093" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1160" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1160" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1163" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1163" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1170" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1170" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1171" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1171" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1172" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1172" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1173" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1173" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1180" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1180" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1182" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1182" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1477" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1477" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1493" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1493" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1577" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1577" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1593" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1593" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1598" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1598" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1745" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1745" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1746" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1746" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1748" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1748" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1759" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1759" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1767" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1767" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1768" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1768" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1776" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1776" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2022" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2022" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2182" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2182" source="CVE" />
    <description>Several vulnerabilities have been discovered in the Linux kernel that may lead to a privilege escalation, denial of service or information leak. The Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures project identifies the following problems: CVE-2010-2524 David Howells reported an issue in the Common Internet File System. Local users could cause arbitrary CIFS shares to be mounted by introducing malicious redirects. CVE-2010-3875 Vasiliy Kulikov discovered an issue in the Linux implementation of the Amateur Radio AX.25 Level 2 protocol. Local users may obtain access to sensitive kernel memory. CVE-2010-4075 Dan Rosenberg reported an issue in the tty layer that may allow local users to obtain access to sensitive kernel memory. CVE-2010-4655 Kees Cook discovered several issues in the ethtool interface which may allow local users with the CAP_NET_ADMIN capability to obtain access to sensitive kernel memory. CVE-2011-0695 Jens Kuehnel reported an issue in the InfiniBand stack. Remote attackers can exploit a race condition to cause a denial of service. CVE-2011-0710 Al Viro reported an issue in the /proc/&amp;lt;pid&amp;gt;/status interface on the s390 architecture. Local users could gain access to sensitive memory in processes they do not own via the task_show_regs entry. CVE-2011-0711 Dan Rosenberg reported an issue in the XFS filesystem. Local users may obtain access to sensitive kernel memory. CVE-2011-0726 Kees Cook reported an issue in the /proc/pid/stat implementation. Local users could learn the text location of a process, defeating protections provided by address space layout randomization. CVE-2011-1010 Timo Warns reported an issue in the Linux support for Mac partition tables. Local users with physical access could cause a denial of service by adding a storage device with a malicious map_count value. CVE-2011-1012 Timo Warns reported an issue in the Linux support for Mac partition tables. Local users with physical access could cause a denial of service by adding a storage device with a malicious map_count value. CVE-2011-1017 Timo Warns reported an issue in the Linux support for LDM partition tables. Users with physical access can gain access to sensitive kernel memory or gain elevated privileges by adding a storage device with a specially crafted LDM partition. CVE-2011-1078 Vasiliy Kulikov discovered an issue in the Bluetooth subsystem. Local users can obtain access to sensitive kernel memory. CVE-2011-1079 Vasiliy Kulikov discovered an issue in the Bluetooth subsystem. Local users with the CAP_NET_ADMIN capability can cause a denial of service. CVE-2011-1080 Vasiliy Kulikov discovered an issue in the Netfilter subsystem. Local users can obtain access to sensitive kernel memory. CVE-2011-1090 Neil Horman discovered a memory leak in the setacl call on NFSv4 filesystems. Local users can exploit this to cause a denial of service. CVE-2011-1093 Johan Hovold reported an issue in the Datagram Congestion Control Protocol implementation. Remote users could cause a denial of service by sending data after closing a socket. CVE-2011-1160 Peter Huewe reported an issue in the Linux kernel's support for TPM security chips. Local users with permission to open the device can gain access to sensitive kernel memory. CVE-2011-1163 Timo Warns reported an issue in the kernel support for Alpha OSF format disk partitions. Users with physical access can gain access to sensitive kernel memory by adding a storage device with a specially crafted OSF partition. CVE-2011-1170 Vasiliy Kulikov reported an issue in the Netfilter arp table implementation. Local users with the CAP_NET_ADMIN capability can gain access to sensitive kernel memory. CVE-2011-1171 Vasiliy Kulikov reported an issue in the Netfilter IP table implementation. Local users with the CAP_NET_ADMIN capability can gain access to sensitive kernel memory. CVE-2011-1172 Vasiliy Kulikov reported an issue in the Netfilter IP6 table implementation. Local users with the CAP_NET_ADMIN capability can gain access to sensitive kernel memory. CVE-2011-1173 Vasiliy Kulikov reported an issue in the Acorn Econet protocol implementation. Local users can obtain access to sensitive kernel memory on systems that use this rare hardware. CVE-2011-1180 Dan Rosenberg reported a buffer overflow in the Information Access Service of the IrDA protocol, used for Infrared devices. Remote attackers within IR device range can cause a denial of service or possibly gain elevated privileges. CVE-2011-1182 Julien Tinnes reported an issue in the rt_sigqueueinfo interface. Local users can generate signals with falsified source pid and uid information. CVE-2011-1477 Dan Rosenberg reported issues in the Open Sound System driver for cards that include a Yamaha FM synthesizer chip. Local users can cause memory corruption resulting in a denial of service. This issue does not affect official Debian Linux image packages as they no longer provide support for OSS. However, custom kernels built from Debians linux-source-2.6.32 may have enabled this configuration and would therefore be vulnerable. CVE-2011-1493 Dan Rosenburg reported two issues in the Linux implementation of the Amateur Radio X.25 PLP protocol. A remote user can cause a denial of service by providing specially crafted facilities fields. CVE-2011-1577 Timo Warns reported an issue in the Linux support for GPT partition tables. Local users with physical access could cause a denial of service by adding a storage device with a malicious partition table header. CVE-2011-1593 Robert Swiecki reported a signednes issue in the next_pidmap function, which can be exploited my local users to cause a denial of service. CVE-2011-1598 Dave Jones reported an issue in the Broadcast Manager Controller Area Network protocol that may allow local users to cause a NULL pointer dereference, resulting in a denial of service. CVE-2011-1745 Vasiliy Kulikov reported an issue in the Linux support for AGP devices. Local users can obtain elevated privileges or cause a denial of service due to missing bounds checking in the AGPIOC_BIND ioctl. On default Debian installations, this is exploitable only by users in the video group. CVE-2011-1746 Vasiliy Kulikov reported an issue in the Linux support for AGP devices. Local users can obtain elevated privileges or cause a denial of service due to missing bounds checking in the agp_allocate_memory and agp_create_user_memory. On default Debian installations, this is exploitable only by users in the video group. CVE-2011-1748 Oliver Kartkopp reported an issue in the Controller Area Network raw socket implementation which permits ocal users to cause a NULL pointer dereference, resulting in a denial of service. CVE-2011-1759 Dan Rosenberg reported an issue in the support for executing &amp;quot;old ABI&amp;quot; binaries on ARM processors. Local users can obtain elevated privileges due to insufficient bounds checking in the semtimedop system call. CVE-2011-1767 Alexecy Dobriyan reported an issue in the GRE over IP implementation. Remote users can cause a denial of service by sending a packet during module initialisation. CVE-2011-1768 Alexecy Dobriyan reported an issue in the IP tunnels implementation. Remote users can cause a denial of service by sending a packet during module initialisation. CVE-2011-1776 Timo Warns reported an issue in the Linux implementation for GUID partitions. Users with physical access can gain access to sensitive kernel memory by adding a storage device with a specially crafted corrupted invalid partition table. CVE-2011-2022 Vasiliy Kulikov reported an issue in the Linux support for AGP devices. Local users can obtain elevated privileges or cause a denial of service due to missing bounds checking in the AGPIOC_UNBIND ioctl. On default Debian installations, this is exploitable only by users in the video group. CVE-2011-2182 Ben Hutchings reported an issue with the fix for CVE-2011-1017 that made it insufficient to resolve the issue.</description>
    <oval_repository>
      <dates>
        <submitted date="2011-09-22T14:25:58-05:00">
          <contributor organization="SecPod Technologies">SecPod Team</contributor>
        </submitted>
        <status_change date="2011-09-22T12:03:41.767-04:00">DRAFT</status_change>
        <status_change date="2011-10-10T04:00:46.570-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2011-10-31T04:01:17.705-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
        <modified comment="EDITED oval:org.mitre.oval:def:12997 - Debian Patch Update" date="2014-06-06T17:05:00.860-04:00">
          <contributor organization="ALTX-SOFT">Sergey Artykhov</contributor>
        </modified>
        <status_change date="2014-06-06T17:07:28.218-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-06-23T04:01:16.975-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
      </dates>
      <status>ACCEPTED</status>
      <min_schema_version>5.4</min_schema_version>
    </oval_repository>
  </metadata>
  <criteria>
    <extend_definition comment="Debian GNU/Linux 5.0 is installed" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:6513" />
    <criterion comment="Installed architecture is all" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:10881" />
    <criterion comment="linux-2.6 DPKG is earlier than 2.6.26-26lenny3" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:44227" />
  </criteria>
</definition>
