<oval-def:definition xmlns:oval-def="http://oval.mitre.org/XMLSchema/oval-definitions-5" class="patch" id="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:13378" version="5">
  <oval-def:metadata>
    <oval-def:title>DSA-1830-1 icedove -- several vulnerabilities</oval-def:title>
    <oval-def:affected family="unix">
      <oval-def:platform>Debian GNU/Linux 5.0</oval-def:platform>
      <oval-def:product>icedove</oval-def:product>
    </oval-def:affected>
    <oval-def:reference ref_id="DSA-1830-1" ref_url="http://lists.debian.org/debian-security-announce/2009/msg00143.html" source="VENDOR" />
    <oval-def:reference ref_id="CVE-2009-0040" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-0040" source="CVE" />
    <oval-def:reference ref_id="CVE-2009-0352" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-0352" source="CVE" />
    <oval-def:reference ref_id="CVE-2009-0353" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-0353" source="CVE" />
    <oval-def:reference ref_id="CVE-2009-0652" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-0652" source="CVE" />
    <oval-def:reference ref_id="CVE-2009-0771" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-0771" source="CVE" />
    <oval-def:reference ref_id="CVE-2009-0772" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-0772" source="CVE" />
    <oval-def:reference ref_id="CVE-2009-0773" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-0773" source="CVE" />
    <oval-def:reference ref_id="CVE-2009-0774" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-0774" source="CVE" />
    <oval-def:reference ref_id="CVE-2009-0776" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-0776" source="CVE" />
    <oval-def:reference ref_id="CVE-2009-1302" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1302" source="CVE" />
    <oval-def:reference ref_id="CVE-2009-1303" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1303" source="CVE" />
    <oval-def:reference ref_id="CVE-2009-1307" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1307" source="CVE" />
    <oval-def:reference ref_id="CVE-2009-1832" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1832" source="CVE" />
    <oval-def:reference ref_id="CVE-2009-1392" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1392" source="CVE" />
    <oval-def:reference ref_id="CVE-2009-1836" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1836" source="CVE" />
    <oval-def:reference ref_id="CVE-2009-1838" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1838" source="CVE" />
    <oval-def:reference ref_id="CVE-2009-1841" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-1841" source="CVE" />
    <oval-def:description>Several remote vulnerabilities have been discovered in the Icedove mail client, an unbranded version of the Thunderbird mail client. The Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures project identifies the following problems: CVE-2009-0040 The execution of arbitrary code might be possible via a crafted PNG file that triggers a free of an uninitialised pointer in the png_read_png function, pCAL chunk handling, or setup of 16-bit gamma tables. CVE-2009-0352 It is possible to execute arbitrary code via vectors related to the layout engine. CVE-2009-0353 It is possible to execute arbitrary code via vectors related to the JavaScript engine. CVE-2009-0652 Bjoern Hoehrmann and Moxie Marlinspike discovered a possible spoofing attack via Unicode box drawing characters in internationalised domain names. CVE-2009-0771 Memory corruption and assertion failures have been discovered in the layout engine, leading to the possible execution of arbitrary code. CVE-2009-0772 The layout engine allows the execution of arbitrary code ia vectors related to nsCSSStyleSheet::GetOwnerNode, events, and garbage collection. CVE-2009-0773 The JavaScript engine is prone to the execution of arbitrary code via several vectors. CVE-2009-0774 The layout engine allows the execution of arbitrary code via vectors related to gczeal. CVE-2009-0776 Georgi Guninski discovered that it is possible to obtain xml data via an issue related to the nsIRDFService. CVE-2009-1302 The browser engine is prone to a possible memory corruption via several vectors. CVE-2009-1303 The browser engine is prone to a possible memory corruption via the nsSVGElement::BindToTree function. CVE-2009-1307 Gregory Fleischer discovered that it is possible to bypass the Same Origin Policy when opening a Flash file via the view-source: scheme. CVE-2009-1832 The possible arbitrary execution of code was discovered via vectors involving &amp;quot;double frame construction.&amp;quot; CVE-2009-1392 Several issues were discovered in the browser engine as used by icedove, which could lead to the possible execution of arbitrary code. CVE-2009-1836 Shuo Chen, Ziqing Mao, Yi-Min Wang and Ming Zhang reported a potential man-in-the-middle attack, when using a proxy due to insufficient checks on a certain proxy response. CVE-2009-1838 moz_bug_r_a4 discovered that it is possible to execute arbitrary JavaScript with chrome privileges due to an error in the garbage-collection implementation. CVE-2009-1841 moz_bug_r_a4 reported that it is possible for scripts from page content to run with elevated privileges and thus potentially executing arbitrary code with the object's chrome privileges. No CVE id yet Bernd Jendrissek discovered a potentially exploitable crash when viewing a multipart/alternative mail message with a text/enhanced part. For the stable distribution, these problems have been fixed in version 2.0.0.22-0lenny1. As indicated in the Etch release notes, security support for the Mozilla products in the oldstable distribution needed to be stopped before the end of the regular Etch security maintenance life cycle. You are strongly encouraged to upgrade to stable or switch to a still supported mail client. For the testing distribution these problems will be fixed soon. For the unstable distribution, these problems have been fixed in version 2.0.0.22-1. We recommend that you upgrade your icedove packages.</oval-def:description>
    <oval-def:oval_repository>
      <oval-def:dates>
        <oval-def:submitted date="2011-10-11T14:18:57-05:00">
          <oval-def:contributor organization="SecPod Technologies">SecPod Team</oval-def:contributor>
        </oval-def:submitted>
        <oval-def:status_change date="2011-10-13T11:28:12.686-04:00">DRAFT</oval-def:status_change>
        <oval-def:status_change date="2011-10-31T04:02:21.219-04:00">INTERIM</oval-def:status_change>
        <oval-def:status_change date="2011-11-21T04:06:15.449-05:00">ACCEPTED</oval-def:status_change>
        <oval-def:modified comment="EDITED oval:org.mitre.oval:def:13378 - Debian Patch Update" date="2014-06-06T16:59:00.298-04:00">
          <oval-def:contributor organization="ALTX-SOFT">Sergey Artykhov</oval-def:contributor>
        </oval-def:modified>
        <oval-def:status_change date="2014-06-06T17:01:37.643-04:00">INTERIM</oval-def:status_change>
        <oval-def:status_change date="2014-06-23T04:02:07.428-04:00">ACCEPTED</oval-def:status_change>
      </oval-def:dates>
      <oval-def:status>ACCEPTED</oval-def:status>
      <oval-def:min_schema_version>5.4</oval-def:min_schema_version>
    </oval-def:oval_repository>
  </oval-def:metadata>
  <oval-def:criteria>
    <oval-def:extend_definition comment="Debian GNU/Linux 5.0 is installed" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:6513" />
    <oval-def:criteria comment="Packages section" operator="OR">
      <oval-def:criterion comment="icedove-dev DPKG is earlier than 2.0.0.22-0lenny1" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:47239" />
      <oval-def:criterion comment="icedove-dbg DPKG is earlier than 2.0.0.22-0lenny1" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:47076" />
      <oval-def:criterion comment="icedove-gnome-support DPKG is earlier than 2.0.0.22-0lenny1" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:48011" />
      <oval-def:criterion comment="icedove DPKG is earlier than 2.0.0.22-0lenny1" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:47541" />
    </oval-def:criteria>
  </oval-def:criteria>
</oval-def:definition>
