<definition xmlns="http://oval.mitre.org/XMLSchema/oval-definitions-5" class="patch" id="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:26754" version="11">
  <metadata>
    <title>ELSA-2014-1143 -- kernel security and bug fix update (Moderate)</title>
    <affected family="unix">
      <platform>Oracle Linux 5</platform>
      <product>kernel</product>
    </affected>
    <reference ref_id="ELSA-2014-1143" ref_url="http://linux.oracle.com/errata/ELSA-2014-1143.html" source="VENDOR" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2014-3917" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2014-3917" source="CVE" />
    <description>The kernel packages contain the Linux kernel, the core of any Linux
operating system.

* An out-of-bounds memory access flaw was found in the Linux kernel&amp;#39;s
system call auditing implementation. On a system with existing audit rules
defined, a local, unprivileged user could use this flaw to leak kernel
memory to user space or, potentially, crash the system. (CVE-2014-3917,
Moderate)

This update also fixes the following bugs:

* A bug in the journaling code (jbd and jbd2) could, under very heavy
workload of fsync() operations, trigger a BUG_ON and result in a kernel
oops. Also, fdatasync() could fail to immediately write out changes in the
file size only. These problems have been resolved by backporting a series
of patches that fixed these problems in the respective code on Red Hat
Enterprise Linux 6. This update also improves performance of ext3 and ext4
file systems. (BZ#1116027)

* Due to a bug in the ext4 code, the fdatasync() system call did not force
the inode size change to be written to the disk if it was the only metadata
change in the file. This could result in the wrong inode size and possible
data loss if the system terminated unexpectedly. The code handling inode
updates has been fixed and fdatasync() now writes data to the disk as
expected in this situation. (BZ#1117665)

* A workaround to a DMA read problem in the tg3 driver was incorrectly
applied to the whole Broadcom 5719 and 5720 chipset family. This workaround
is valid only to the A0 revision of the 5719 chips and for other revisions
and chips causes occasional Tx timeouts. This update correctly applies the
aforementioned workaround only to the A0 revision of the 5719 chips.
(BZ#1121017)

* Due to a bug in the page writeback code, the system could become
unresponsive when being under memory pressure and heavy NFS load. This
update fixes the code responsible for handling of dirty pages, and dirty
page write outs no longer flood the work queue. (BZ#1125246)

All kernel users are advised to upgrade to these updated packages, which
contain backported patches to correct these issues. The system must be
rebooted for this update to take effect.</description>
    <oval_repository>
      <dates>
        <submitted date="2014-10-01T10:20:32">
          <contributor organization="ALTX-SOFT">Sergey Artykhov</contributor>
        </submitted>
        <status_change date="2014-10-10T18:35:26.914-04:00">DRAFT</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-10-27T04:01:31.793-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-11-17T04:00:49.298-05:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
      </dates>
      <status>ACCEPTED</status>
      <min_schema_version>5.3</min_schema_version>
    </oval_repository>
  </metadata>
  <criteria>
    <extend_definition comment="Oracle Linux 5.x" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:15459" />
    <criteria comment="Packages match section" operator="OR">
      <criterion comment="kernel RPM is earlier than 0:2.6.18-371.12.1.el5" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:124905" />
      <criterion comment="kernel-PAE RPM is earlier than 0:2.6.18-371.12.1.el5" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:124911" />
      <criterion comment="kernel-PAE-devel RPM is earlier than 0:2.6.18-371.12.1.el5" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:124926" />
      <criterion comment="kernel-debug RPM is earlier than 0:2.6.18-371.12.1.el5" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:124876" />
      <criterion comment="kernel-debug-devel RPM is earlier than 0:2.6.18-371.12.1.el5" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:124264" />
      <criterion comment="kernel-devel RPM is earlier than 0:2.6.18-371.12.1.el5" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:124863" />
      <criterion comment="kernel-doc RPM is earlier than 0:2.6.18-371.12.1.el5" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:124878" />
      <criterion comment="kernel-headers RPM is earlier than 0:2.6.18-371.12.1.el5" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:124627" />
      <criterion comment="kernel-xen RPM is earlier than 0:2.6.18-371.12.1.el5" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:124852" />
      <criterion comment="kernel-xen-devel RPM is earlier than 0:2.6.18-371.12.1.el5" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:123937" />
    </criteria>
  </criteria>
</definition>
