<definition xmlns="http://oval.mitre.org/XMLSchema/oval-definitions-5" class="patch" id="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:28643" version="14">
  <metadata>
    <title>ELSA-2015-1115 -- Oracle openssl</title>
    <affected family="unix">
      <platform>Oracle Linux 6</platform>
      <product>openssl</product>
    </affected>
    <reference ref_id="ELSA-2015-1115" ref_url="https://oss.oracle.com/pipermail/el-errata/2015-June/005125.html" source="VENDOR" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2015-1791" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2015-1791" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2015-0209" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2015-0209" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2014-8176" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2014-8176" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2015-1789" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2015-1789" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2015-1790" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2015-1790" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2015-1792" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2015-1792" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2015-3216" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2015-3216" source="CVE" />
    <description>OpenSSL is a toolkit that implements the Secure Sockets Layer  and Transport Layer Security  protocols, as well as a full-strength, general purpose cryptography library. An invalid free flaw was found in the way OpenSSL handled certain DTLS handshake messages. A malicious DTLS client or server could cause a DTLS server or client using OpenSSL to crash or, potentially, execute arbitrary code.  A flaw was found in the way the OpenSSL packages shipped with Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6 and 7 performed locking in the ssleay_rand_bytes function. This issue could possibly cause a multi-threaded application using OpenSSL to perform an out-of-bounds read and crash.  An out-of-bounds read flaw was found in the X509_cmp_time function of OpenSSL. A specially crafted X.509 certificate or a Certificate Revocation List  could possibly cause a TLS/SSL server or client using OpenSSL to crash.  A race condition was found in the session handling code of OpenSSL. This issue could possibly cause a multi-threaded TLS/SSL client using OpenSSL to double free session ticket data and crash.  A flaw was found in the way OpenSSL handled Cryptographic Message Syntax  messages. A CMS message with an unknown hash function identifier could cause an application using OpenSSL to enter an infinite loop.  A NULL pointer dereference was found in the way OpenSSL handled certain PKCS#7 inputs. A specially crafted PKCS#7 input with missing EncryptedContent data could cause an application using OpenSSL to crash.  Red Hat would like to thank the OpenSSL project for reporting CVE-2014-8176, CVE-2015-1789, CVE-2015-1790, CVE-2015-1791 and CVE-2015-1792 flaws. Upstream acknowledges Praveen Kariyanahalli and Ivan Fratric as the original reporters of CVE-2014-8176, Robert Swiecki and Hanno Bock as the original reporters of CVE-2015-1789, Michal Zalewski as the original reporter of CVE-2015-1790, Emilia Kasper as the original report of CVE-2015-1791 and Johannes Bauer as the original reporter of CVE-2015-1792. All openssl users are advised to upgrade to these updated packages, which contain backported patches to correct these issues. For the update to take effect, all services linked to the OpenSSL library must be restarted, or the system rebooted.</description>
    <oval_repository>
      <dates>
        <submitted date="2015-06-16T09:20:00-05:00">
          <contributor organization="SecPod Technologies">SecPod Team</contributor>
        </submitted>
        <status_change date="2015-06-18T09:29:47.951-04:00">DRAFT</status_change>
        <status_change date="2015-07-06T04:00:18.739-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2015-07-27T04:00:24.495-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
      </dates>
      <status>ACCEPTED</status>
      <min_schema_version>5.3</min_schema_version>
    </oval_repository>
  </metadata>
  <criteria operator="AND">
    <extend_definition comment="Oracle Linux 6.x" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:16594" />
    <criteria comment="All dependent packages of openssl" operator="OR">
      <criterion comment="openssl is earlier than 0:1.0.1e-30.el6_6.11 for i686" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:138647" />
      <criterion comment="openssl-devel is earlier than 0:1.0.1e-30.el6_6.11 for i686" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:138021" />
      <criterion comment="openssl-perl is earlier than 0:1.0.1e-30.el6_6.11 for i686" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:138997" />
      <criterion comment="openssl-static is earlier than 0:1.0.1e-30.el6_6.11 for i686" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:138548" />
      <criterion comment="openssl is earlier than 0:1.0.1e-30.el6_6.11 for x86_64" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:138674" />
      <criterion comment="openssl-devel is earlier than 0:1.0.1e-30.el6_6.11 for x86_64" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:138445" />
      <criterion comment="openssl-perl is earlier than 0:1.0.1e-30.el6_6.11 for x86_64" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:138995" />
      <criterion comment="openssl-static is earlier than 0:1.0.1e-30.el6_6.11 for x86_64" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:138809" />
    </criteria>
  </criteria>
</definition>
