<definition xmlns="http://oval.mitre.org/XMLSchema/oval-definitions-5" class="patch" id="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:26215" version="12">
  <metadata>
    <title>RHSA-2014:1023: kernel security and bug fix update (Important)</title>
    <affected family="unix">
      <platform>Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7</platform>
      <platform>CentOS Linux 7</platform>
      <product>kernel</product>
    </affected>
    <reference ref_id="RHSA-2014:1023-00" ref_url="https://rhn.redhat.com/errata/RHSA-2014-1023.html" source="VENDOR" />
    <reference ref_id="CESA-2014:1023" source="CESA" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2014-0181" ref_url="https://www.redhat.com/security/data/cve/CVE-2014-0181.html" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2014-2672" ref_url="https://www.redhat.com/security/data/cve/CVE-2014-2672.html" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2014-2673" ref_url="https://www.redhat.com/security/data/cve/CVE-2014-2673.html" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2014-2706" ref_url="https://www.redhat.com/security/data/cve/CVE-2014-2706.html" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2014-3534" ref_url="https://www.redhat.com/security/data/cve/CVE-2014-3534.html" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2014-4667" ref_url="https://www.redhat.com/security/data/cve/CVE-2014-4667.html" source="CVE" />
    <description>The kernel packages contain the Linux kernel, the core of any Linux
operating system.

* It was found that Linux kernel's ptrace subsystem did not properly
sanitize the address-space-control bits when the program-status word (PSW)
was being set. On IBM S/390 systems, a local, unprivileged user could use
this flaw to set address-space-control bits to the kernel space, and thus
gain read and write access to kernel memory. (CVE-2014-3534, Important)

* It was found that the permission checks performed by the Linux kernel
when a netlink message was received were not sufficient. A local,
unprivileged user could potentially bypass these restrictions by passing a
netlink socket as stdout or stderr to a more privileged process and
altering the output of this process. (CVE-2014-0181, Moderate)

* It was found that a remote attacker could use a race condition flaw in
the ath_tx_aggr_sleep() function to crash the system by creating large
network traffic on the system's Atheros 9k wireless network adapter.
(CVE-2014-2672, Moderate)

* A flaw was found in the way the Linux kernel performed forking inside of
a transaction. A local, unprivileged user on a PowerPC system that supports
transactional memory could use this flaw to crash the system.
(CVE-2014-2673, Moderate)

* A race condition flaw was found in the way the Linux kernel's mac80211
subsystem implementation handled synchronization between TX and STA wake-up
code paths. A remote attacker could use this flaw to crash the system.
(CVE-2014-2706, Moderate)

* An integer underflow flaw was found in the way the Linux kernel's Stream
Control Transmission Protocol (SCTP) implementation processed certain
COOKIE_ECHO packets. By sending a specially crafted SCTP packet, a remote
attacker could use this flaw to prevent legitimate connections to a
particular SCTP server socket to be made. (CVE-2014-4667, Moderate)

Red Hat would like to thank Martin Schwidefsky of IBM for reporting
CVE-2014-3534, Andy Lutomirski for reporting CVE-2014-0181, and Gopal Reddy
Kodudula of Nokia Siemens Networks for reporting CVE-2014-4667.

This update also fixes the following bugs:

* Due to a NULL pointer dereference bug in the IPIP and SIT tunneling code,
a kernel panic could be triggered when using IPIP or SIT tunnels with
IPsec. This update restructures the related code to avoid a NULL pointer
dereference and the kernel no longer panics when using IPIP or SIT tunnels
with IPsec. (BZ#1114957)

* Previously, an IBM POWER8 system could terminate unexpectedly when the
kernel received an IRQ while handling a transactional memory re-checkpoint
critical section. This update ensures that IRQs are disabled in this
situation and the problem no longer occurs. (BZ#1113150)

* A missing read memory barrier, rmb(), in the bnx2x driver caused the
kernel to crash under various circumstances. This problem has been fixed
by adding an rmb() call to the relevant place in the bnx2x code.
(BZ#1107721)

* The hpwdt driver previously emitted a panic message that was misleading
on certain HP systems. This update ensures that upon a kernel panic, hpwdt
displays information valid on all HP systems. (BZ#1096961)

* The qla2xxx driver has been upgraded to version 8.06.00.08.07.0-k3,
which provides a number of bug fixes over the previous version in order to
correct various timeout problems with the mailbox commands. (BZ#1112389)

* The SCSI mid-layer could retry an I/O operation indefinitely if a storage
array repeatedly returned a CHECK CONDITION status to that I/O operation
but the sense data was invalid. This update fixes the problem by limiting
a time for which is such an I/O operation retried. (BZ#1114468)

All kernel users are advised to upgrade to these updated packages, which
contain backported patches to correct these issues. The system must be
rebooted for this update to take effect.</description>
    <oval_repository>
      <dates>
        <submitted date="2014-08-18T12:09:18">
          <contributor organization="ALTX-SOFT">Sergey Artykhov</contributor>
        </submitted>
        <status_change date="2014-09-05T14:28:58.924-04:00">DRAFT</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-09-22T04:00:41.994-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-10-13T04:00:24.651-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
      </dates>
      <status>ACCEPTED</status>
      <min_schema_version>5.3</min_schema_version>
    </oval_repository>
  </metadata>
  <criteria>
    <criteria comment="Redhat 7 or Centos 7 release" operator="OR">
      <extend_definition comment="The operating system installed on the system is Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:24953" />
      <extend_definition comment="The operating system installed on the system is CentOS Linux 7.x" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:24773" />
    </criteria>
    <criteria comment="Packages section" operator="OR">
      <criterion comment="kernel is earlier than 0:3.10.0-123.6.3.el7" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:122457" />
      <criterion comment="kernel-abi-whitelists is earlier than 0:3.10.0-123.6.3.el7" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:121995" />
      <criterion comment="kernel-bootwrapper is earlier than 0:3.10.0-123.6.3.el7" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:121766" />
      <criterion comment="kernel-debug is earlier than 0:3.10.0-123.6.3.el7" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:122401" />
      <criterion comment="kernel-debug-devel is earlier than 0:3.10.0-123.6.3.el7" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:122201" />
      <criterion comment="kernel-devel is earlier than 0:3.10.0-123.6.3.el7" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:121841" />
      <criterion comment="kernel-doc is earlier than 0:3.10.0-123.6.3.el7" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:122305" />
      <criterion comment="kernel-headers is earlier than 0:3.10.0-123.6.3.el7" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:122459" />
      <criterion comment="kernel-kdump is earlier than 0:3.10.0-123.6.3.el7" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:122528" />
      <criterion comment="kernel-kdump-devel is earlier than 0:3.10.0-123.6.3.el7" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:122427" />
      <criterion comment="kernel-tools is earlier than 0:3.10.0-123.6.3.el7" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:122484" />
      <criterion comment="kernel-tools-libs is earlier than 0:3.10.0-123.6.3.el7" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:122158" />
      <criterion comment="kernel-tools-libs-devel is earlier than 0:3.10.0-123.6.3.el7" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:121979" />
      <criterion comment="perf is earlier than 0:3.10.0-123.6.3.el7" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:122137" />
      <criterion comment="python-perf is earlier than 0:3.10.0-123.6.3.el7" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:122530" />
    </criteria>
  </criteria>
</definition>
