<definition xmlns="http://oval.mitre.org/XMLSchema/oval-definitions-5" class="patch" id="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:12759" version="21">
  <metadata>
    <title>DSA-2115-1 moodle -- several</title>
    <affected family="unix">
      <platform>Debian GNU/Linux 5.0</platform>
      <product>moodle</product>
    </affected>
    <reference ref_id="DSA-2115-1" ref_url="http://lists.debian.org/debian-security-announce/2010/msg00164.html" source="VENDOR" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-1613" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-1613" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-1614" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-1614" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-1615" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-1615" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-1616" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-1616" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-1617" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-1617" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-1618" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-1618" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-1619" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-1619" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-2228" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-2228" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-2229" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-2229" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-2230" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-2230" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-2231" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-2231" source="CVE" />
    <description>Several remote vulnerabilities have been discovered in Moodle, a course management system. The Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures project identifies the following problems: CVE-2010-1613 Moodle does not enable the &amp;quot;Regenerate session id during login&amp;quot; setting by default, which makes it easier for remote attackers to conduct session fixation attacks. CVE-2010-1614 Multiple cross-site scripting vulnerabilities allow remote attackers to inject arbitrary web script or HTML via vectors related to the Login-As feature or when the global search feature is enabled, unspecified global search forms in the Global Search Engine. CVE-2010-1615 Multiple SQL injection vulnerabilities allow remote attackers to execute arbitrary SQL commands via vectors related to the add_to_log function in mod/wiki/view.php in the wiki module, or &amp;quot;data validation in some forms elements&amp;quot; related to lib/form/selectgroups.php. CVE-2010-1616 Moodle can create new roles when restoring a course, which allows teachers to create new accounts even if they do not have the moodle/user:create capability. CVE-2010-1617 user/view.php does not properly check a role, which allows remote authenticated users to obtain the full names of other users via the course profile page. CVE-2010-1618 A Cross-site scripting vulnerability in the phpCAS client library allows remote attackers to inject arbitrary web script or HTML via a crafted URL, which is not properly handled in an error message. CVE-2010-1619 A Cross-site scripting vulnerability in the fix_non_standard_entities function in the KSES HTML text cleaning library allows remote attackers to inject arbitrary web script or HTML via crafted HTML entities. CVE-2010-2228 A Cross-site scripting vulnerability in the MNET access-control interface allows remote attackers to inject arbitrary web script or HTML via vectors involving extended characters in a username. CVE-2010-2229 Multiple cross-site scripting vulnerabilities in blog/index.php allow remote attackers to inject arbitrary web script or HTML via unspecified parameters. CVE-2010-2230 The KSES text cleaning filter in lib/weblib.php does not properly handle vbscript URIs, which allows remote authenticated users to conduct cross-site scripting attacks via HTML input. CVE-2010-2231 A Cross-site request forgery vulnerability in report/overview/report.php in the quiz module allows remote attackers to hijack the authentication of arbitrary users for requests that delete quiz attempts via the attemptid parameter. This security update switches to a new upstream version and requires database updates. For the stable distribution, these problems have been fixed in version 1.8.13-1. For the unstable distribution, these problems have been fixed in version 1.9.9.dfsg2-1. We recommend that you upgrade your moodle package.</description>
    <oval_repository>
      <dates>
        <submitted date="2011-06-30T06:21:19">
          <contributor organization="SecPod Technologies">SecPod Team</contributor>
        </submitted>
        <status_change date="2011-06-30T14:54:04.869-04:00">DRAFT</status_change>
        <status_change date="2011-07-18T04:00:30.700-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2011-08-08T04:00:37.675-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
        <modified comment="EDITED oval:org.mitre.oval:def:12759 - Debian Patch Update" date="2014-06-06T17:07:00.556-04:00">
          <contributor organization="ALTX-SOFT">Sergey Artykhov</contributor>
        </modified>
        <status_change date="2014-06-06T17:09:28.182-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-06-23T04:00:44.632-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
      </dates>
      <status>ACCEPTED</status>
      <min_schema_version>5.4</min_schema_version>
    </oval_repository>
  </metadata>
  <criteria>
    <extend_definition comment="Debian GNU/Linux 5.0 is installed" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:6513" />
    <criterion comment="Installed architecture is all" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:10881" />
    <criterion comment="moodle DPKG is earlier than 1.8.13-1" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:42564" />
  </criteria>
</definition>
