<definition xmlns="http://oval.mitre.org/XMLSchema/oval-definitions-5" class="patch" id="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:12161" version="21">
  <metadata>
    <title>DSA-2143-1 mysql-dfsg-5.0 -- several vulnerabilities</title>
    <affected family="unix">
      <platform>Debian GNU/Linux 5.0</platform>
      <product>mysql-dfsg-5.0</product>
    </affected>
    <reference ref_id="DSA-2143-1" ref_url="http://lists.debian.org/debian-security-announce/2011/msg00007.html" source="VENDOR" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-3677" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-3677" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-3680" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-3680" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-3681" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-3681" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-3682" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-3682" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-3833" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-3833" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-3834" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-3834" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-3835" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-3835" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-3836" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-3836" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-3837" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-3837" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-3838" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-3838" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-3840" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-3840" source="CVE" />
    <description>Several vulnerabilities have been discovered in the MySQL database server. The Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures project identifies the following problems: CVE-2010-3677 It was discovered that MySQL allows remote authenticated users to cause a denial of service via a join query that uses a table with a unique SET column. CVE-2010-3680 It was discovered that MySQL allows remote authenticated users to cause a denial of service by creating temporary tables while using InnoDB, which triggers an assertion failure. CVE-2010-3681 It was discovered that MySQL allows remote authenticated users to cause a denial of service by using the HANDLER interface and performing &amp;quot;alternate reads from two indexes on a table,&amp;quot; which triggers an assertion failure. CVE-2010-3682 It was discovered that MySQL incorrectly handled use of EXPLAIN with certain queries. An authenticated user could crash the server. CVE-2010-3833 It was discovered that MySQL incorrectly handled propagation during evaluation of arguments to extreme-value functions. An authenticated user could crash the server. CVE-2010-3834 It was discovered that MySQL incorrectly handled materializing a derived table that required a temporary table for grouping. An authenticated user could crash the server. CVE-2010-3835 It was discovered that MySQL incorrectly handled certain user-variable assignment expressions that are evaluated in a logical expression context. An authenticated user could crash the server. CVE-2010-3836 It was discovered that MySQL incorrectly handled pre-evaluation of LIKE predicates during view preparation. An authenticated user could crash the server. CVE-2010-3837 It was discovered that MySQL incorrectly handled using GROUP_CONCAT and WITH ROLLUP together. An authenticated user could crash the server. CVE-2010-3838 It was discovered that MySQL incorrectly handled certain queries using a mixed list of numeric and LONGBLOB arguments to the GREATEST or LEAST functions. An authenticated user could crash the server. CVE-2010-3840 It was discovered that MySQL incorrectly handled improper WKB data passed to the PolyFromWKB function. An authenticated user could crash the server.</description>
    <oval_repository>
      <dates>
        <submitted date="2011-09-22T22:31:49-05:00">
          <contributor organization="SecPod Technologies">SecPod Team</contributor>
        </submitted>
        <status_change date="2011-09-22T12:03:11.959-04:00">DRAFT</status_change>
        <status_change date="2011-10-10T04:00:07.375-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2011-10-31T04:00:14.169-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
        <modified comment="EDITED oval:org.mitre.oval:def:12161 - Debian Patch Update" date="2014-06-30T16:50:00.552-04:00">
          <contributor organization="ALTX-SOFT">Sergey Artykhov</contributor>
        </modified>
        <status_change date="2014-06-30T16:52:19.887-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-07-21T04:00:12.350-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
      </dates>
      <status>ACCEPTED</status>
      <min_schema_version>5.4</min_schema_version>
    </oval_repository>
  </metadata>
  <criteria>
    <extend_definition comment="Debian GNU/Linux 5.0 is installed" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:6513" />
    <criterion comment="Installed architecture is all" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:10881" />
    <criterion comment="mysql-dfsg-5.0 DPKG is earlier than 5.0.51a-24+lenny5" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:43753" />
  </criteria>
</definition>
