<definition xmlns="http://oval.mitre.org/XMLSchema/oval-definitions-5" class="patch" id="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:26851" version="13">
  <metadata>
    <title>RHSA-2014:1194: conga security and bug fix update (Moderate)</title>
    <affected family="unix">
      <platform>Red Hat Enterprise Linux 5</platform>
      <platform>CentOS Linux 5</platform>
      <product>conga</product>
    </affected>
    <reference ref_id="RHSA-2014:1194-00" ref_url="https://rhn.redhat.com/errata/RHSA-2014-1194.html" source="VENDOR" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2012-5485" ref_url="https://www.redhat.com/security/data/cve/CVE-2012-5485.html" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2012-5486" ref_url="https://www.redhat.com/security/data/cve/CVE-2012-5486.html" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2012-5488" ref_url="https://www.redhat.com/security/data/cve/CVE-2012-5488.html" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2012-5497" ref_url="https://www.redhat.com/security/data/cve/CVE-2012-5497.html" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2012-5498" ref_url="https://www.redhat.com/security/data/cve/CVE-2012-5498.html" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2012-5499" ref_url="https://www.redhat.com/security/data/cve/CVE-2012-5499.html" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2012-5500" ref_url="https://www.redhat.com/security/data/cve/CVE-2012-5500.html" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2013-6496" ref_url="https://www.redhat.com/security/data/cve/CVE-2013-6496.html" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2014-3521" ref_url="https://www.redhat.com/security/data/cve/CVE-2014-3521.html" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CESA-2014:1194" ref_url="http://lists.centos.org/pipermail/centos-announce/2014-September/020611.html" source="CESA-2014:1194" />
    <description>The Conga project is a management system for remote workstations.
It consists of luci, which is a secure web-based front end, and ricci,
which is a secure daemon that dispatches incoming messages to underlying
management modules.

It was discovered that Plone, included as a part of luci, did not properly
protect the administrator interface (control panel). A remote attacker
could use this flaw to inject a specially crafted Python statement or
script into Plone's restricted Python sandbox that, when the administrator
interface was accessed, would be executed with the privileges of that
administrator user. (CVE-2012-5485)

It was discovered that Plone, included as a part of luci, did not properly
sanitize HTTP headers provided within certain URL requests. A remote
attacker could use a specially crafted URL that, when processed, would
cause the injected HTTP headers to be returned as a part of the Plone HTTP
response, potentially allowing the attacker to perform other more advanced
attacks. (CVE-2012-5486)

Multiple information leak flaws were found in the way conga processed luci
site extension-related URL requests. A remote, unauthenticated attacker
could issue a specially crafted HTTP request that, when processed, would
result in unauthorized information disclosure. (CVE-2013-6496)

It was discovered that various components in the luci site
extension-related URLs were not properly restricted to administrative
users. A remote, authenticated attacker could escalate their privileges to
perform certain actions that should be restricted to administrative users,
such as adding users and systems, and viewing log data. (CVE-2014-3521)

It was discovered that Plone, included as a part of luci, did not properly
protect the privilege of running RestrictedPython scripts. A remote
attacker could use a specially crafted URL that, when processed, would
allow the attacker to submit and perform expensive computations or, in
conjunction with other attacks, be able to access or alter privileged
information. (CVE-2012-5488)

It was discovered that Plone, included as a part of luci, did not properly
enforce permissions checks on the membership database. A remote attacker
could use a specially crafted URL that, when processed, could allow the
attacker to enumerate user account names. (CVE-2012-5497)

It was discovered that Plone, included as a part of luci, did not properly
handle the processing of requests for certain collections. A remote
attacker could use a specially crafted URL that, when processed, would lead
to excessive I/O and/or cache resource consumption. (CVE-2012-5498)

It was discovered that Plone, included as a part of luci, did not properly
handle the processing of very large values passed to an internal utility
function. A remote attacker could use a specially crafted URL that, when
processed, would lead to excessive memory consumption. (CVE-2012-5499)

It was discovered that Plone, included as a part of luci, allowed a remote
anonymous user to change titles of content items due to improper
permissions checks. (CVE-2012-5500)

The CVE-2014-3521 issue was discovered by Radek Steiger of Red Hat, and the
CVE-2013-6496 issue was discovered by Jan Pokorny of Red Hat.

In addition, these updated conga packages include several bug fixes.
Space precludes documenting all of these changes in this advisory.
Users are directed to the Red Hat Enterprise Linux 5.11 Technical Notes,
linked to in the References section, for information on the most
significant of these changes

All conga users are advised to upgrade to these updated packages, which
contain backported patches to correct these issues. After installing this
update, the luci and ricci services will be restarted automatically.</description>
    <oval_repository>
      <dates>
        <submitted date="2014-09-26T11:25:02">
          <contributor organization="ALTX-SOFT">Sergey Artykhov</contributor>
        </submitted>
        <status_change date="2014-09-29T12:07:06.903-04:00">DRAFT</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-10-20T04:00:58.744-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-11-10T04:02:08.581-05:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
        <modified comment="EDITED oval:org.mitre.oval:def:26851 - CentOS criteria were added where necessary, descriptions were shortened." date="2015-03-23T14:40:00.799-04:00">
          <contributor organization="ALTX-SOFT">Maria Mikhno</contributor>
        </modified>
        <status_change date="2015-03-23T14:45:51.746-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2015-04-13T04:00:12.483-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
      </dates>
      <status>ACCEPTED</status>
      <min_schema_version>5.3</min_schema_version>
    </oval_repository>
  </metadata>
  <criteria>
    <extend_definition comment="The operating system installed on the system is CentOS Linux 5.x" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:15802" />
    <criteria comment="Packages match section" operator="OR">
      <criterion comment="luci is earlier than 0:0.12.2-81.el5.centos" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:138442" />
      <criterion comment="ricci is earlier than 0:0.12.2-81.el5.centos" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:138312" />
    </criteria>
  </criteria>
</definition>
