<definition xmlns="http://oval.mitre.org/XMLSchema/oval-definitions-5" class="patch" id="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:12874" version="22">
  <metadata>
    <title>DSA-2153-1 linux-2.6 -- privilege escalation/denial of service/information leak</title>
    <affected family="unix">
      <platform>Debian GNU/Linux 5.0</platform>
      <product>linux-2.6</product>
    </affected>
    <reference ref_id="DSA-2153-1" ref_url="http://lists.debian.org/debian-security-announce/2011/msg00017.html" source="VENDOR" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-0435" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-0435" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-3699" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-3699" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-4158" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-4158" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-4162" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-4162" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-4163" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-4163" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-4242" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-4242" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-4243" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-4243" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-4248" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-4248" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-4249" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-4249" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-4258" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-4258" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-4342" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-4342" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-4346" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-4346" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-4526" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-4526" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-4527" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-4527" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-4529" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-4529" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-4565" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-4565" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-4649" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-4649" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-4656" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-4656" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-4668" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-4668" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-0521" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-0521" source="CVE" />
    <description>Several vulnerabilities have been discovered in the Linux kernel that may lead to a privilege escalation, denial of service or information leak. The Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures project identifies the following problems: CVE-2010-0435 Gleb Napatov reported an issue in the KVM subsystem that allows virtual machines to cause a denial of service of the host machine by executing mov to/from DR instructions. CVE-2010-3699 Keir Fraser provided a fix for an issue in the Xen subsystem. A guest can cause a denial of service on the host by retaining a leaked reference to a device. This can result in a zombie domain, xenwatch process hangs, and xm command failures. CVE-2010-4158 Dan Rosenberg discovered an issue in the socket filters subsystem, allowing local unprivileged users to obtain the contents of sensitive kernel memory. CVE-2010-4162 Dan Rosenberg discovered an overflow issue in the block I/O subsystem that allows local users to map large numbers of pages, resulting in a denial of service due to invocation of the out of memory killer. CVE-2010-4163 Dan Rosenberg discovered an issue in the block I/O subsystem. Due to improper validation of iov segments, local users can trigger a kernel panic resulting in a denial of service. CVE-2010-4242 Alan Cox reported an issue in the Bluetooth subsystem. Local users with sufficient permission to access HCI UART devices can cause a denial of service due to a missing check for an existing tty write operation. CVE-2010-4243 Brad Spengler reported a denial-of-service issue in the kernel memory accounting system. By passing large argv/envp values to exec, local users can cause the out of memory killer to kill processes owned by other users. CVE-2010-4248 Oleg Nesterov reported an issue in the POSIX CPU timers subsystem. Local users can cause a denial of service due to incorrect assumptions about thread group leader behavior. CVE-2010-4249 Vegard Nossum reported an issue with the UNIX socket garbage collector. Local users can consume all of LOWMEM and decrease system performance by overloading the system with inflight sockets. CVE-2010-4258 Nelson Elhage reported an issue in Linux oops handling. Local users may be able to obtain elevated privileges if they are able to trigger an oops with a process" fs set to KERNEL_DS. CVE-2010-4342 Nelson Elhage reported an issue in the econet protocol. Remote attackers can cause a denial of service by sending an Acorn Universal Networking packet over UDP. CVE-2010-4346 Tavis Ormandy discovered an issue in the install_special_mapping routine which allows local users to bypass the mmap_min_addr security restriction. Combined with an otherwise low severity local denial of service vulnerability, a local user could obtain elevated privileges. CVE-2010-4526 Eugene Teo reported a race condition in the Linux SCTP implementation. Remote users can cause a denial of service by transmitting an ICMP unreachable message to a locked socket. CVE-2010-4527 Dan Rosenberg reported two issues in the OSS soundcard driver. Local users with access to the device may contain access to sensitive kernel memory or cause a buffer overflow, potentially leading to an escalation of privileges. CVE-2010-4529 Dan Rosenberg reported an issue in the Linux kernel IrDA socket implementation on non-x86 architectures. Local users may be able to gain access to sensitive kernel memory via a specially crafted IRLMP_ENUMDEVICES getsockopt call. CVE-2010-4565 Dan Rosenberg reported an issue in the Linux CAN protocol implementation. Local users can obtain the address of a kernel heap object which might help facilitate system exploitation. CVE-2010-4649 Dan Carpenter reported an issue in the uverb handling of the InfiniBand subsystem. A potential buffer overflow may allow local users to cause a denial of service by passing in a large cmd.ne value. CVE-2010-4656 Kees Cook reported an issue in the driver for I/O-Warrior USB devices. Local users with access to these devices maybe able to overrun kernel buffers, resulting in a denial of service or privilege escalation. CVE-2010-4668 Dan Rosenberg reported an issue in the block subsystem. A local user can cause a denial of service by submitting certain 0-length I/O requests. CVE-2011-0521 Dan Carpenter reported an issue in the DVB driver for AV7110 cards. Local users can pass a negative info-&amp;gt;num value, corrupting kernel memory and causing a denial of service.</description>
    <oval_repository>
      <dates>
        <submitted date="2011-09-22T15:44:48-05:00">
          <contributor organization="SecPod Technologies">SecPod Team</contributor>
        </submitted>
        <status_change date="2011-09-22T12:03:12.735-04:00">DRAFT</status_change>
        <status_change date="2011-10-10T04:00:35.448-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2011-10-31T04:01:00.126-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
        <modified comment="EDITED oval:org.mitre.oval:def:12874 - Debian Patch Update" date="2014-06-06T17:34:00.215-04:00">
          <contributor organization="ALTX-SOFT">Sergey Artykhov</contributor>
        </modified>
        <status_change date="2014-06-06T17:36:28.393-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-06-23T04:01:00.648-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
      </dates>
      <status>ACCEPTED</status>
      <min_schema_version>5.4</min_schema_version>
    </oval_repository>
  </metadata>
  <criteria>
    <extend_definition comment="Debian GNU/Linux 5.0 is installed" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:6513" />
    <criterion comment="Installed architecture is all" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:10881" />
    <criterion comment="linux-2.6 DPKG is earlier than 2.6.26-26lenny2" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:43727" />
  </criteria>
</definition>
