<definition xmlns="http://oval.mitre.org/XMLSchema/oval-definitions-5" class="patch" id="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:26934" version="4">
  <metadata>
    <title>RHSA-2011:1741 -- php-pear security and bug fix update (Low)</title>
    <affected family="unix">
      <platform>Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6</platform>
      <product>php-pear</product>
    </affected>
    <reference ref_id="RHSA-2011:1741" ref_url="https://rhn.redhat.com/errata/RHSA-2011-1741.html" source="VENDOR" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1072" ref_url="https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1072" source="CVE" />
    <description>The php-pear package contains the PHP Extension and Application Repository
(PEAR), a framework and distribution system for reusable PHP components.

It was found that the &amp;quot;pear&amp;quot; command created temporary files in an insecure
way when installing packages. A malicious, local user could use this flaw
to conduct a symbolic link attack, allowing them to overwrite the contents
of arbitrary files accessible to the victim running the &amp;quot;pear install&amp;quot;
command. (CVE-2011-1072)

This update also fixes the following bugs:

* The php-pear package has been upgraded to version 1.9.4, which provides a
number of bug fixes over the previous version. (BZ#651897)

* Prior to this update, php-pear created a cache in the
&amp;quot;/var/cache/php-pear/&amp;quot; directory when attempting to list all packages. As a
consequence, php-pear failed to create or update the cache file as a
regular user without sufficient file permissions and could not list all
packages. With this update, php-pear no longer fails if writing to the
cache directory is not permitted. Now, all packages are listed as expected.
(BZ#747361)

All users of php-pear are advised to upgrade to this updated package, which
corrects these issues.</description>
    <oval_repository>
      <dates>
        <submitted date="2014-10-28T18:16:05">
          <contributor organization="ALTX-SOFT">Sergey Artykhov</contributor>
        </submitted>
        <status_change date="2014-10-29T12:47:55.396-04:00">DRAFT</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-11-17T04:01:11.635-05:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-12-08T04:00:26.522-05:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
      </dates>
      <status>ACCEPTED</status>
      <min_schema_version>5.10</min_schema_version>
    </oval_repository>
  </metadata>
  <criteria>
    <extend_definition comment="The operating system installed on the system is Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:20273" />
    <criterion comment="php-pear is earlier than 0:1.9.4-4.el6" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:126140" />
  </criteria>
</definition>
