<definition xmlns="http://oval.mitre.org/XMLSchema/oval-definitions-5" class="patch" id="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:15414" version="22">
  <metadata>
    <title>DSA-2389-1 linux-2.6 -- privilege escalation/denial of service/information leak</title>
    <affected family="unix">
      <platform>Debian GNU/Linux 6.0</platform>
      <platform>Debian GNU/kFreeBSD 6.0</platform>
      <product>linux-2.6</product>
    </affected>
    <reference ref_id="DSA-2389-1" ref_url="http://lists.debian.org/debian-security-announce/2012/msg00013.html" source="VENDOR" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2183" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2183" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2213" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2213" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2898" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2898" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-3353" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-3353" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-4077" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-4077" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-4110" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-4110" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-4127" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-4127" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-4611" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-4611" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-4622" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-4622" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-4914" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-4914" source="CVE" />
    <description>Several vulnerabilities have been discovered in the Linux kernel that may lead to a denial of service or privilege escalation. The Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures project identifies the following problems: CVE-2011-2183 Andrea Righi reported an issue in KSM, a memory-saving de-duplication feature. By exploiting a race with exiting tasks, local users can cause a kernel oops, resulting in a denial of service. CVE-2011-2213 Dan Rosenberg discovered an issue in the INET socket monitoring interface. Local users could cause a denial of service by injecting code and causing the kernel to execute an infinite loop. CVE-2011-2898 Eric Dumazet reported an information leak in the raw packet socket implementation. CVE-2011-3353 Han-Wen Nienhuys reported a local denial of service issue issue in the FUSE support in the linux kernel. Local users could cause a buffer overflow, leading to a kernel oops and resulting in a denial of service. CVE-2011-4077 Carlos Maiolino reported an issue in the XFS filesystem. A local user with the ability to mount a filesystem could corrupt memory resulting in a denial of service or possibly gain elevated privileges. CVE-2011-4110 David Howells reported an issue in the kernel's access key retention system which allow local users to cause a kernel oops leading to a denial of service. CVE-2011-4127 Paolo Bonzini of Red Hat reported an issue in the ioctl passthrough support for SCSI devices. Users with permission to access restricted portions of a device can obtain access to the entire device by way of the SG_IO ioctl. This could be exploited by a local user or privileged VM guest to achieve a privilege escalation. CVE-2011-4611 Maynard Johnson reported an issue with the perf support on POWER7 systems that allows local users to cause a denial of service. CVE-2011-4622 Jan Kiszka reported an issue in the KVM PIT timer support. Local users with the permission to use KVM can cause a denial of service by starting a PIT timer without first setting up the irqchip. CVE-2011-4914 Ben Hutchings reported various bounds checking issues within the ROSE protocol support in the kernel. Remote users could possibly use this to gain access to sensitive memory or cause a denial of service.</description>
    <oval_repository>
      <dates>
        <submitted date="2012-03-29T02:10:09-05:00">
          <contributor organization="SecPod Technologies">SecPod Team</contributor>
        </submitted>
        <status_change date="2012-03-29T10:57:09.482-04:00">DRAFT</status_change>
        <status_change date="2012-04-16T04:07:43.535-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2012-05-07T04:02:14.345-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
        <modified comment="EDITED oval:org.mitre.oval:def:15414 - Debian Patch Update" date="2014-06-06T17:11:00.221-04:00">
          <contributor organization="ALTX-SOFT">Sergey Artykhov</contributor>
        </modified>
        <status_change date="2014-06-06T17:13:16.608-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-06-23T04:03:47.772-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
      </dates>
      <status>ACCEPTED</status>
      <min_schema_version>5.6</min_schema_version>
    </oval_repository>
  </metadata>
  <criteria>
    <extend_definition comment="Debian 6.0 is installed" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:12959" />
    <criteria comment="GNU/Linux or GNU/kFreeBSD kernel" operator="OR">
      <extend_definition comment="Debian GNU/Linux is installed" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:24894" />
      <extend_definition comment="Debian GNU/kFreeBSD is installed" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:24698" />
    </criteria>
    <criterion comment="Installed architecture is all" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:10881" />
    <criterion comment="linux-2.6 DPKG is earlier than 2.6.32-39squeeze1" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:78541" />
  </criteria>
</definition>
