<definition xmlns="http://oval.mitre.org/XMLSchema/oval-definitions-5" class="patch" id="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:26652" version="10">
  <metadata>
    <title>RHSA-2013:1635 -- pacemaker security, bug fix, and enhancement update (Low)</title>
    <affected family="unix">
      <platform>Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6</platform>
      <platform>CentOS Linux 6</platform>
      <product>pacemaker</product>
    </affected>
    <reference ref_id="RHSA-2013:1635" ref_url="https://rhn.redhat.com/errata/RHSA-2013-1635.html" source="VENDOR" />
    <reference ref_id="CESA-2013:1635" ref_url="http://lists.centos.org/pipermail/centos-cr-announce/2013-November/001037.html" source="CESA-2013:1635" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2013-0281" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2013-0281" source="CVE" />
    <description>Pacemaker is a high-availability cluster resource manager with a powerful
policy engine.

A denial of service flaw was found in the way Pacemaker performed
authentication and processing of remote connections in certain
circumstances. When Pacemaker was configured to allow remote Cluster
Information Base (CIB) configuration or resource management, a remote
attacker could use this flaw to cause Pacemaker to block indefinitely
(preventing it from serving other requests). (CVE-2013-0281)

Note: The default Pacemaker configuration in Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6 has
the remote CIB management functionality disabled.

The pacemaker package has been upgraded to upstream version 1.1.10, which
provides a number of bug fixes and enhancements over the previous version:

* Pacemaker no longer assumes unknown cman nodes are safely stopped.

* The core dump file now converts all exit codes into positive &amp;#39;errno&amp;#39;
values.

* Pacemaker ensures a return to a stable state after too many fencing
failures, and initiates a shutdown if a node claimed to be fenced is still
active.

* The crm_error tool adds the ability to list and print error symbols.

* The crm_resource command allows individual resources to be reprobed, and
implements the &amp;quot;--ban&amp;quot; option for moving resources away from nodes.
The &amp;quot;--clear&amp;quot; option has replaced the &amp;quot;--unmove&amp;quot; option. Also, crm_resource
now supports OCF tracing when using the &amp;quot;--force&amp;quot; option.

* The IPC mechanism restores the ability for members of the haclient group
to connect to the cluster.

* The Policy Engine daemon allows active nodes in the current membership to
be fenced without quorum.

* Policy Engine now suppresses meaningless IDs when displaying anonymous
clone status, supports maintenance mode for a single node, and correctly
handles the recovered resources before they are operated on.

* XML configuration files are now checked for non-printing characters and
replaced with their octal equivalent when exporting XML text. Also, a more
reliable buffer allocation strategy has been implemented to prevent
lockups.

(BZ#987355)

Additional bug fixes:

* The &amp;quot;crm_resource --move&amp;quot; command was designed for atomic resources and
could not handle resources on clones, masters, or slaves present on
multiple nodes. Consequently, crm_resource could not obtain enough
information to move a resource and did not perform any action. The &amp;quot;--ban&amp;quot;
and &amp;quot;--clear&amp;quot; options have been added to allow the administrator to
instruct the cluster unambiguously. Clone, master, and slave resources can
now be navigated within the cluster as expected. (BZ#902407)

* The hacluster user account did not have a user identification (UID) or
group identification (GID) number reserved on the system. Thus, UID and GID
values were picked randomly during the installation process. The UID and
GID number 189 was reserved for hacluster and is now used consistently for
all installations. (BZ#908450)

* Certain clusters used node host names that did not match the output of
the &amp;quot;uname -n&amp;quot; command. Thus, the default node name used by the crm_standby
and crm_failcount commands was incorrect and caused the cluster to ignore
the update by the administrator. The crm_node command is now used instead
of the uname utility in helper scripts. As a result, the cluster behaves as
expected. (BZ#913093)

* Due to incorrect return code handling, internal recovery logic of the
crm_mon utility was not executed when a configuration updated failed to
apply, leading to an assertion failure. Return codes are now checked
correctly, and the recovery of an expected error state is now handled
transparently. (BZ#951371)

* cman&amp;#39;s automatic unfencing feature failed when combined with Pacemaker.
Support for automated unfencing in Pacemaker has been added, and the
unwanted behavior no longer occurs. (BZ#996850)

All pacemaker users are advised to upgrade to these updated packages, which
contain backported patches to correct these issues and add these
enhancements.</description>
    <oval_repository>
      <dates>
        <submitted date="2014-10-28T18:15:41">
          <contributor organization="ALTX-SOFT">Sergey Artykhov</contributor>
        </submitted>
        <status_change date="2014-10-29T12:47:51.526-04:00">DRAFT</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-11-17T04:00:42.401-05:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-12-08T04:00:20.978-05:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
      </dates>
      <status>ACCEPTED</status>
      <min_schema_version>5.3</min_schema_version>
    </oval_repository>
  </metadata>
  <criteria operator="OR">
    <criteria comment="Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6 release section">
      <extend_definition comment="The operating system installed on the system is Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:20273" />
      <criterion comment="pacemaker-debuginfo is earlier than 0:1.1.10-14.el6" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:125891" />
    </criteria>
    <criteria comment="Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6 and CentOS Linux 6 release section">
      <criteria comment="Operation system section" operator="OR">
        <extend_definition comment="The operating system installed on the system is Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:20273" />
        <extend_definition comment="The operating system installed on the system is CentOS Linux 6.x" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:16337" />
      </criteria>
      <criterion comment="pacemaker-remote is earlier than 0:1.1.10-14.el6" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:125581" />
    </criteria>
    <criteria comment="CentOS Linux 6 release section">
      <extend_definition comment="The operating system installed on the system is CentOS Linux 6.x" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:16337" />
      <criteria comment="Packages match section" operator="OR">
        <criterion comment="pacemaker is earlier than 0:1.1.10-14.el6" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:125758" />
        <criterion comment="pacemaker-cli is earlier than 0:1.1.10-14.el6" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:125991" />
        <criterion comment="pacemaker-cluster-libs is earlier than 0:1.1.10-14.el6" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:126043" />
        <criterion comment="pacemaker-cts is earlier than 0:1.1.10-14.el6" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:125912" />
        <criterion comment="pacemaker-doc is earlier than 0:1.1.10-14.el6" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:125397" />
        <criterion comment="pacemaker-libs is earlier than 0:1.1.10-14.el6" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:126048" />
        <criterion comment="pacemaker-libs-devel is earlier than 0:1.1.10-14.el6" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:125701" />
      </criteria>
    </criteria>
  </criteria>
</definition>
