<definition xmlns="http://oval.mitre.org/XMLSchema/oval-definitions-5" class="patch" id="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:14888" version="22">
  <metadata>
    <title>DSA-2303-2 linux-2.6 -- privilege escalation/denial of service/information leak</title>
    <affected family="unix">
      <platform>Debian GNU/Linux 6.0</platform>
      <platform>Debian GNU/kFreeBSD 6.0</platform>
      <product>linux-2.6</product>
    </affected>
    <reference ref_id="DSA-2303-2" ref_url="http://lists.debian.org/debian-security-announce/2011/msg00180.html" source="VENDOR" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1020" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1020" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1576" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1576" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2484" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2484" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2491" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2491" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2492" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2492" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2495" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2495" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2496" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2496" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2497" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2497" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2517" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2517" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2525" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2525" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2700" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2700" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2723" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2723" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2905" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2905" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2909" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2909" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2918" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2918" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2928" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2928" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-3188" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-3188" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-3191" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-3191" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1768" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1768" source="CVE" />
    <description>The linux-2.6 and user-mode-linux upgrades from DSA-2303-1 has caused a regression that can result in an oops during invalid accesses to /proc/&amp;lt;pid&amp;gt;/maps files. The text of the original advisory is reproduced for reference: Several vulnerabilities have been discovered in the Linux kernel that may lead to a denial of service or privilege escalation. The Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures project identifies the following problems: CVE-2011-1020 Kees Cook discovered an issue in the /proc filesystem that allows local users to gain access to sensitive process information after execution of a setuid binary. CVE-2011-1576 Ryan Sweat discovered an issue in the VLAN implementation. Local users may be able to cause a kernel memory leak, resulting in a denial of service. CVE-2011-2484 Vasiliy Kulikov of Openwall discovered that the number of exit handlers that a process can register is not capped, resulting in local denial of service through resource exhaustion. CVE-2011-2491 Vasily Averin discovered an issue with the NFS locking implementation. A malicious NFS server can cause a client to hang indefinitely in an unlock call. CVE-2011-2492 Marek Kroemeke and Filip Palian discovered that uninitialised struct elements in the Bluetooth subsystem could lead to a leak of sensitive kernel memory through leaked stack memory. CVE-2011-2495 Vasiliy Kulikov of Openwall discovered that the io file of a process" proc directory was world-readable, resulting in local information disclosure of information such as password lengths. CVE-2011-2496 Robert Swiecki discovered that mremap could be abused for local denial of service by triggering a BUG_ON assert. CVE-2011-2497 Dan Rosenberg discovered an integer underflow in the Bluetooth subsystem, which could lead to denial of service or privilege escalation. CVE-2011-2517 It was discovered that the netlink-based wireless configuration interface performed insufficient length validation when parsing SSIDs, resulting in buffer overflows. Local users with the CAP_NET_ADMIN capability can cause a denial of service. CVE-2011-2525 Ben Pfaff reported an issue in the network scheduling code. A local user could cause a denial of service by sending a specially crafted netlink message. CVE-2011-2700 Mauro Carvalho Chehab of Red Hat reported a buffer overflow issue in the driver for the Si4713 FM Radio Transmitter driver used by N900 devices. Local users could exploit this issue to cause a denial of service or potentially gain elevated privileges. CVE-2011-2723 Brent Meshier reported an issue in the GRO implementation. This can be exploited by remote users to create a denial of service in certain network device configurations. CVE-2011-2905 Christian Ohm discovered that the "perf" analysis tool searches for its config files in the current working directory. This could lead to denial of service or potential privilege escalation if a user with elevated privileges is tricked into running "perf" in a directory under the control of the attacker. CVE-2011-2909 Vasiliy Kulikov of Openwall discovered that a programming error in the Comedi driver could lead to the information disclosure through leaked stack memory. CVE-2011-2918 Vince Weaver discovered that incorrect handling of software event overflows in the "perf" analysis tool could lead to local denial of service. CVE-2011-2928 Timo Warns discovered that insufficient validation of Be filesystem images could lead to local denial of service if a malformed filesystem image is mounted. CVE-2011-3188 Dan Kaminsky reported a weakness of the sequence number generation in the TCP protocol implementation. This can be used by remote attackers to inject packets into an active session. CVE-2011-3191 Darren Lavender reported an issue in the Common Internet File System. A malicious file server could cause memory corruption leading to a denial of service. This update also includes a fix for a regression introduced with the previous security fix for CVE-2011-1768</description>
    <oval_repository>
      <dates>
        <submitted date="2012-03-29T02:10:09-05:00">
          <contributor organization="SecPod Technologies">SecPod Team</contributor>
        </submitted>
        <status_change date="2012-03-29T10:56:48.814-04:00">DRAFT</status_change>
        <status_change date="2012-04-16T04:06:11.095-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2012-05-07T04:00:39.398-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
        <modified comment="EDITED oval:org.mitre.oval:def:14888 - Debian Patch Update" date="2014-06-06T17:13:00.482-04:00">
          <contributor organization="ALTX-SOFT">Sergey Artykhov</contributor>
        </modified>
        <status_change date="2014-06-06T17:15:15.489-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-06-23T04:03:17.667-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
      </dates>
      <status>ACCEPTED</status>
      <min_schema_version>5.6</min_schema_version>
    </oval_repository>
  </metadata>
  <criteria>
    <extend_definition comment="Debian 6.0 is installed" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:12959" />
    <criteria comment="GNU/Linux or GNU/kFreeBSD kernel" operator="OR">
      <extend_definition comment="Debian GNU/Linux is installed" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:24894" />
      <extend_definition comment="Debian GNU/kFreeBSD is installed" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:24698" />
    </criteria>
    <criterion comment="Installed architecture is all" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:10881" />
    <criterion comment="linux-2.6 DPKG is earlier than 2.6.32-35squeeze2" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:77752" />
  </criteria>
</definition>
