<definition xmlns="http://oval.mitre.org/XMLSchema/oval-definitions-5" class="patch" id="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:14257" version="22">
  <metadata>
    <title>DSA-2310-1 linux-2.6 -- privilege escalation/denial of service/information leak</title>
    <affected family="unix">
      <platform>Debian GNU/Linux 5.0</platform>
      <product>linux-2.6</product>
    </affected>
    <reference ref_id="DSA-2310-1" ref_url="http://lists.debian.org/debian-security-announce/2011/msg00187.html" source="VENDOR" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2009-4067" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2009-4067" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-0712" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-0712" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1020" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1020" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2209" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2209" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2211" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2211" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2213" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2213" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2484" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2484" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2491" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2491" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2492" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2492" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2495" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2495" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2496" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2496" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2497" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2497" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2525" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2525" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-2928" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-2928" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-3188" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-3188" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-3191" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-3191" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2011-1768" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1768" source="CVE" />
    <description>Several vulnerabilities have been discovered in the Linux kernel that may lead to a privilege escalation, denial of service or information leak. The Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures project identifies the following problems: CVE-2009-4067 Rafael Dominguez Vega of MWR InfoSecurity reported an issue in the auerswald module, a driver for Auerswald PBX/System Telephone USB devices. Attackers with physical access to a system's USB ports could obtain elevated privileges using a specially crafted USB device. CVE-2011-0712 Rafael Dominguez Vega of MWR InfoSecurity reported an issue in the caiaq module, a USB driver for Native Instruments USB audio devices. Attackers with physical access to a system's USB ports could obtain elevated privileges using a specially crafted USB device. CVE-2011-1020 Kees Cook discovered an issue in the /proc filesystem that allows local users to gain access to sensitive process information after execution of a setuid binary. CVE-2011-2209 Dan Rosenberg discovered an issue in the osf_sysinfo system call on the alpha architecture. Local users could obtain access to sensitive kernel memory. CVE-2011-2211 Dan Rosenberg discovered an issue in the osf_wait4 system call on the alpha architecture permitting local users to gain elevated privileges. CVE-2011-2213 Dan Rosenberg discovered an issue in the INET socket monitoring interface. Local users could cause a denial of service by injecting code and causing the kernel to execute an infinite loop. CVE-2011-2484 Vasiliy Kulikov of Openwall discovered that the number of exit handlers that a process can register is not capped, resulting in local denial of service through resource exhaustion. CVE-2011-2491 Vasily Averin discovered an issue with the NFS locking implementation. A malicious NFS server can cause a client to hang indefinitely in an unlock call. CVE-2011-2492 Marek Kroemeke and Filip Palian discovered that uninitialised struct elements in the Bluetooth subsystem could lead to a leak of sensitive kernel memory through leaked stack memory. CVE-2011-2495 Vasiliy Kulikov of Openwall discovered that the io file of a process" proc directory was world-readable, resulting in local information disclosure of information such as password lengths. CVE-2011-2496 Robert Swiecki discovered that mremap could be abused for local denial of service by triggering a BUG_ON assert. CVE-2011-2497 Dan Rosenberg discovered an integer underflow in the Bluetooth subsystem, which could lead to denial of service or privilege escalation. CVE-2011-2525 Ben Pfaff reported an issue in the network scheduling code. A local user could cause a denial of service by sending a specially crafted netlink message. CVE-2011-2928 Timo Warns discovered that insufficient validation of Be filesystem images could lead to local denial of service if a malformed filesystem image is mounted. CVE-2011-3188 Dan Kaminsky reported a weakness of the sequence number generation in the TCP protocol implementation. This can be used by remote attackers to inject packets into an active session. CVE-2011-3191 Darren Lavender reported an issue in the Common Internet File System. A malicious file server could cause memory corruption leading to a denial of service. This update also includes a fix for a regression introduced with the previous security fix for CVE-2011-1768</description>
    <oval_repository>
      <dates>
        <submitted date="2012-03-29T02:10:09-05:00">
          <contributor organization="SecPod Technologies">SecPod Team</contributor>
        </submitted>
        <status_change date="2012-03-29T10:56:57.259-04:00">DRAFT</status_change>
        <status_change date="2012-04-16T04:02:57.193-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2012-05-07T04:00:06.696-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
        <modified comment="EDITED oval:org.mitre.oval:def:14257 - Debian Patch Update" date="2014-06-06T17:13:00.482-04:00">
          <contributor organization="ALTX-SOFT">Sergey Artykhov</contributor>
        </modified>
        <status_change date="2014-06-06T17:15:12.840-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-06-23T04:03:09.238-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
      </dates>
      <status>ACCEPTED</status>
      <min_schema_version>5.4</min_schema_version>
    </oval_repository>
  </metadata>
  <criteria>
    <extend_definition comment="Debian GNU/Linux 5.0 is installed" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:6513" />
    <criterion comment="Installed architecture is all" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:10881" />
    <criterion comment="linux-2.6 DPKG is earlier than 2.6.26-26lenny4" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:78416" />
  </criteria>
</definition>
