<definition xmlns="http://oval.mitre.org/XMLSchema/oval-definitions-5" class="patch" id="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:12858" version="22">
  <metadata>
    <title>DSA-2151-1 openoffice.org -- several</title>
    <affected family="unix">
      <platform>Debian GNU/Linux 5.0</platform>
      <product>openoffice.org</product>
    </affected>
    <reference ref_id="DSA-2151-1" ref_url="http://lists.debian.org/debian-security-announce/2011/msg00015.html" source="VENDOR" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-3450" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-3450" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-3451" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-3451" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-3452" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-3452" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-3453" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-3453" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-3454" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-3454" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-3689" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-3689" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-4253" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-4253" source="CVE" />
    <reference ref_id="CVE-2010-4643" ref_url="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2010-4643" source="CVE" />
    <description>Several security related problems have been discovered in the OpenOffice.org package that allows malformed documents to trick the system into crashes or even the execution of arbitrary code. CVE-2010-3450 During an internal security audit within Red Hat, a directory traversal vulnerability has been discovered in the way OpenOffice.org 3.1.1 through 3.2.1 processes XML filter files. If a local user is tricked into opening a specially-crafted OOo XML filters package file, this problem could allow remote attackers to create or overwrite arbitrary files belonging to local user or, potentially, execute arbitrary code. CVE-2010-3451 During his work as a consultant at Virtual Security Research, Dan Rosenberg discovered a vulnerability in OpenOffice.org's RTF parsing functionality. Opening a maliciously crafted RTF document can caus an out-of-bounds memory read into previously allocated heap memory, which may lead to the execution of arbitrary code. CVE-2010-3452 Dan Rosenberg discovered a vulnerability in the RTF file parser which can be leveraged by attackers to achieve arbitrary code execution by convincing a victim to open a maliciously crafted RTF file. CVE-2010-3453 As part of his work with Virtual Security Research, Dan Rosenberg discovered a vulnerability in the WW8ListManager::WW8ListManager function of OpenOffice.org that allows a maliciously crafted file to cause the execution of arbitrary code. CVE-2010-3454 As part of his work with Virtual Security Research, Dan Rosenberg discovered a vulnerability in the WW8DopTypography::ReadFromMem function in OpenOffice.org that may be exploited by a maliciously crafted file which allowins an attacker to control program flow and potentially execute arbitrary code. CVE-2010-3689 Dmitri Gribenko discovered that the soffice script does not treat an empty LD_LIBRARY_PATH variable like an unset one, may lead to the execution of arbitrary code. CVE-2010-4253 A heap based buffer overflow has been discovered with unknown impact. CVE-2010-4643 A vulnerability has been discovered in the way OpenOffice.org handles TGA graphics which can be tricked by a specially crafted TGA file that could cause the program to crash due to a heap-based buffer overflow with unknown impact.</description>
    <oval_repository>
      <dates>
        <submitted date="2011-09-22T20:07:03-05:00">
          <contributor organization="SecPod Technologies">SecPod Team</contributor>
        </submitted>
        <status_change date="2011-09-22T12:03:14.676-04:00">DRAFT</status_change>
        <status_change date="2011-10-10T04:00:32.714-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2011-10-31T04:00:57.204-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
        <modified comment="EDITED oval:org.mitre.oval:def:12858 - Debian Patch Update" date="2014-06-06T17:07:00.556-04:00">
          <contributor organization="ALTX-SOFT">Sergey Artykhov</contributor>
        </modified>
        <status_change date="2014-06-06T17:09:37.050-04:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2014-06-23T04:00:59.023-04:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
        <modified comment="EDITED oval:org.mitre.oval:ste:13071 - Modified Debian patches to correct Epochs." date="2015-02-04T10:32:00.631-05:00">
          <contributor organization="ALTX-SOFT">Maria Mikhno</contributor>
        </modified>
        <status_change date="2015-02-04T10:36:25.074-05:00">INTERIM</status_change>
        <status_change date="2015-02-23T04:00:16.598-05:00">ACCEPTED</status_change>
      </dates>
      <status>ACCEPTED</status>
      <min_schema_version>5.4</min_schema_version>
    </oval_repository>
  </metadata>
  <criteria>
    <extend_definition comment="Debian GNU/Linux 5.0 is installed" definition_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:def:6513" />
    <criterion comment="Installed architecture is all" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:10881" />
    <criterion comment="openoffice.org DPKG is earlier than 1:2.4.1+dfsg-1+lenny11" test_ref="oval:org.mitre.oval:tst:43396" />
  </criteria>
</definition>
